music
音楽
applause
拍手
So today we actually have two keynote speakers
今日は実際に 2 人の基調講演者がいます
but
しかし
Ah, academician Zhang Shenghua, he is very polite
ああ、学者の張生華さん、彼はとても礼儀正しいです
he
他
Ah, a self-proclaimed shadow speaker
ああ、自称影のスピーカーです
He will speak for 20 minutes
彼は20分間話します
So
それで
So the speaker is Li Guangdi
つまり、講演者は李広帝です
Teacher, the two of them performed together
先生、二人で共演しましたよ
Joint performance
ジョイントパフォーマンス
What about today's keynote speaker, Dr. Li Guangdi?
今日の基調講演者、李広帝博士はどうですか？
Is a researcher at the Institute of History, Academia Sinica
中央研究院歴史研究所の研究員です
then arizona state university
その後アリゾナ州立大学
PhD in Archaeological Anthropology
考古人類学の博士号
He's mostly doing ecological archaeology
彼は主に生態考古学を研究しています
that is, through archaeological remains
つまり、考古学的な遺跡を通して
to estimate
見積もる
recovery
回復
Then the food resources at that time
そうすると当時の食糧資源は
Ecological environment and climate
生態環境と気候
including the population
人口も含めて
Including the time the site was occupied, etc.
敷地が占有されていた時間等も含みます。
So this is a highly integrated technology
これは高度に統合されたテクノロジーです
imagination
想像力
one of archaeological work and more
考古学的な研究のひとつなど
Your knowledge is very important
あなたの知識は非常に重要です
his main
彼のメイン
Except for the Academia Sinica
中央研究院を除く
He is also in the School of Anthropology of Tsing University
彼は清大学人類学部にも在籍しています。
That is to say, the Earth Science Department of Normal University
つまり師範大学地球科学科です。
and Tainan University of the Arts
台南芸術大学
first lesson
最初のレッスン
Then his main scope of work
その後、彼の主な仕事の範囲は
is in
いる
Hengchun Peninsula
恒春半島
and Tainan Science Park
台南サイエンスパーク
I can testify that he is almost
私は彼がほぼそうなっていると証言できます
Ah, a representative of public opinion
ああ、世論の代表よ
I remember twenty, thirty or twenty years ago
20年、30年、あるいは20年前のことを覚えています
when i went there once
一度そこに行ったとき
He knows almost everyone there
彼はそこにいるほぼ全員を知っています
everyone around
周りのみんな
so i know he's over there
だから私は彼がそこにいるのを知っています
deep plowing
秘密の種を深く耕す
There is quite a deep
かなり奥が深いですね
local strength
地元の力
Today's shadow speaker is Academician Zhang Zhenghua
今日の影の講演者は学者の張正華です
Well, he's also a research fellow at the History Institute of the Majestic Academy.
そうですね、彼はマジェスティックアカデミーの歴史研究所の研究員でもあります。
He is a Ph.D. from Harvard University
彼はハーバード大学の博士号を取得しています
His main research interest is Taiwan
彼の主な研究対象は台湾です
Southeast Asia
東南アジア
and this archaeological site in South China
そして中国南部のこの遺跡
Research
研究
He was in 2002 to 2006
彼は2002年から2006年まで
secondment single
出向独身
Director of National Taiwan Museum of Prehistory
国立台湾先史博物館館長
Chang Hsien is of course the current archaeological leader in Taiwan
張賢は言うまでもなく、現在の台湾の考古学の指導者です。
Three of the many jobs he now performs
彼が現在行っている多くの仕事のうちの 3 つ
One is the archaeology of Nanke
一つは南溪の考古学です。
One is the archeology of Baxian Cave
一つは八仙洞の考古学です。
that is a very important site
それはとても重要なサイトです
One is to lead the underwater archeology team of Academia Sinica
1つは中央研究院の水中考古学チームを率いることです。
He was elected as an academician of Academia Sinica on the Third World in 2014
彼は 2014 年に第三世界に関する中央研究院の学者に選出されました。
The topic the two of them are going to talk about today is Nanke Archeology
今日二人が話すテーマは南柯考古学
5000 years of discovery of Taiwan
台湾発見5000年
You may have noticed that Nanke Archeology has been going on for 20 years
南渓考古学は20年前から続いていることに気づいたかもしれません
Voted one of the top ten archaeological sites in the world last year
昨年、世界トップ 10 の考古学遺跡の 1 つに選ばれました
Then I just noticed
それで今気づいたんですが
This is the first time that Nanke archeology has been included in the knowledge award test report
南柯考古学が知識賞の試験報告書に含まれるのは今回が初めてです。
Their work I think this opportunity is very rare
彼らの作品 こんな機会はなかなかないと思います
Then this archaeological site
つまりこの遺跡は
Worked without knowledge for 20 years
知識もなく20年間働きました
said
言った
touched area
触れたエリア
2000 hectares of independent
2000ヘクタールの独立した土地
A total of 70 archaeological sites were discovered
合計70の遺跡が発見された
Large-scale excavations were carried out at 34 of them
そのうち 34 か所で大規模な発掘調査が行われた
The total excavated area reached more than 120,000 average meters
総掘削面積は平均12万メートル以上に達した
More than 120,000 square meters
120,000平方メートル以上
The abundance of archaeological materials unearthed
発掘された豊富な考古資料
all kinds of colors
あらゆる種類の色
Because he used to be the director of this institute
彼はかつてこの研究所の所長だったから
So I also visited
ということで私も訪れてみました
very rich
とても裕福な
I'm afraid it's Asia, I dare not talk nonsense
残念ですが、ここはアジアです、ナンセンスなことは言いません
One of the largest archaeological sites
最大規模の考古学遺跡の 1 つ
Whether it is naughty, stone, jade, bone, etc.
エッチなものでも、石でも、翡翠でも、骨でも。
Taiwan's first dog
台湾初の犬
Taiwan's first
台湾初
all from this ruins
すべてこのサイトから
There are more than 2,000 unearthed
2000個以上発掘されている
More than 2000 dramas
2000本以上のドラマ
spanned over 5000 years
5000年以上にわたって
rare archaeological site
珍しい遺跡
As the climate of the South Island and foot of the world
南の島、世界の麓の気候として
It is very important to migrate
移行することは非常に重要です
It is very important to understand this issue
この問題を理解することは非常に重要です
Well, this archaeological team is currently conducting
さて、この考古学チームは現在、
Arrangement and analysis of cultural relics unearthed in one place in twenty one places
21ヶ所1ヶ所出土文化財の整理と分析
Sorting and analysis, wow, are two different things again.
分類と分析は、またしても別の話です。
Archeology sucks.
考古学はダメだ。
And it's very hard, working with the soil all day long
一日中土をいじるのはとても大変です
It's really hard work
本当に大変な仕事です
After that, it needs to be analyzed and sorted out.
その後、分析して整理する必要があります。
Still need to organize and analyze
まだまだ整理と分析が必要
Also do DNA testing
DNA検査もする
Gotta do all kinds of this wow amazing amazing
あらゆる種類のことをしなければなりません、すごい、すごい、すごい
Then this site enriches the new era of Taiwan
そして、このサイトは台湾の新しい時代を豊かにします
Understanding of Early Human Lifestyles
初期の人類のライフスタイルの理解
Also provides more information about the ancient Austronesian peoples
古代オーストロネシア民族についての詳しい情報も提供します。
New Evidence and Understanding of Ocean-to-Ocean Diffusion from the Asian Continent
アジア大陸からの海洋から海洋への拡散に関する新たな証拠と理解
Of course, this site is because of the huge size of Thailand
もちろん、このサイトはタイの広大さのためです
I can't introduce them all here
ここでは全部は紹介できませんが、
Should we just welcome Academician Zhang Zhenghua to do camp performances first?
まずはアカデミー会員の張正華氏を迎えてキャンプ公演を行うべきでしょうか？
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you, Dean Wang, for letting me come here to give an introduction.
ディーン・ワンさん、紹介のためにここに来てくれてありがとう。
Thank you very much too
こちらもありがとうございました
be honest
正直に言う
Come and listen to our Nanke archaeological report
ぜひ南柯考古学レポートを聞いてください。
I think today this archaeological
今日私はこの考古学的なことを考えています
This knowledge feast of the past
過去のこの知識の饗宴
I've said it twice
2回言いました
So this time I would like to invite our colleagues
そこで今回は同僚たちを招待したいと思います
Mr. Li Huangqing will talk about it
李黄清氏がそれについて話します
Later, our dean helped me to return the ticket.
その後、学部長がチケットを返却するのを手伝ってくれました。
Say no, the two of you
いいえ、二人とも言ってください
So finally we assign
それで最後に割り当てます
I said I'll be the intro
私がイントロになるって言ったのに
Or ask our colleagues to do this
または、同僚にこれを行うように依頼してください
a major report
重大な報告
So what I'm going to talk about today is
それで、今日私が話そうとしていることは、
I just want to make this Nanke archaeological
この南溪を考古学的にしたいだけです
ins and outs
内と外
can give a little introduction
少し紹介できます
Everyone can have an impression
誰もが印象に残る
Then the following enters our topic
次に、以下が私たちのトピックに入ります
How Nanke Archeology Discovered Taiwan for 5,000 Years
南柯考古学は5000年間台湾をどのように発見したか
And how to discover the five thousand years of Taiwan
台湾の5000年を知る方法
this is the topic of today's speech
これが今日のスピーチのテーマです
then this
それからこれ
I think the reason why
その理由は、
The vice president will take a fancy to us
副大統領は私たちを気に入ってくれるでしょう
let us come
来ましょう
come here to sing the play
劇を歌いにここに来てください
Basically these two brands
基本的にはこの2ブランド
Because in December last year we participated in a
というのも、昨年の12月に参加したのが、
This is an archeology of a world
これは世界の考古学です
this is in shanghai
ここは上海にあります
One held in Shanghai in 2015
2015年に上海で開催されたもの
The World Archaeological Forum
世界考古学フォーラム
Then we propose this project
そこでこのプロジェクトを提案します
A Description of Our One Contents
Oneコンテンツの説明
then by this
それからこれによって
Selected as the so-called top ten archaeological discoveries in the world
いわゆる世界の考古学的発見トップ10に選ばれる
The first is field archaeological discoveries
1つ目は野外考古学的発見です
so we get two medals
それでメダルが2つもらえる
I was a little disappointed when I got it
届いたときはちょっとがっかりしました
looks heavy
重そうに見える
Later, I found out that it was probably signed inside.
後で分かったのですが、おそらく中にサインが入っていたのだと思います。
Du layer of gold on the outside
外側の金の二重層
If two gold medals
金メダルが２つあれば
That's pretty worth it
それはかなり価値があります
but it will
しかし、そうなります
This is what we do for the Central Court
これが私たちが中央裁判所のために行っていることです
You can also fight for a little glory
ちょっとした栄光のために戦うこともできる
because this is about
これは約ですので
There are 40 top scholars and experts in the world
世界のトップの学者や専門家は40人います
jointly reviewed
共同レビュー
and then to grant
それから許可する
So we also feel honored
だから私たちも光栄に思います
to get such an award
このような賞を獲得するには
then this is
それならこれは
So today I probably want to basically explain the ins and outs of this plan.
そこで今日は、この計画の詳細について基本的に説明したいと思います。
First of all, let me give you a report
まずはご報告させていただきます
I think our basic archeology is the study of history
私たちの基本的な考古学は歴史の研究だと思います
What about our special Taiwan archeology in Taiwan
台湾での特別な台湾考古学についてはどうですか？
Basically, it is necessary to study and study the history of Taiwan.
基本的には台湾の歴史を勉強して勉強する必要があります。
But what about Taiwan's history?
しかし、台湾の歴史はどうだったのでしょうか？
written history is very short
書かれた歴史は非常に短い
Everyone knows about 300 to 400 years
誰もが300年から400年について知っています
very short
非常短
So we all know this
だから私たちは皆これを知っています
In fact, what is the history of our people in Taiwan?
実際、台湾の人々の歴史は、
It's definitely not 300 or 400 years now
決して300年も400年も経っていない
Now at least according to our current archaeological data
少なくとも現在の考古学的データによれば、
Just now the vice president of the academy mentioned that I am personally in Baixuandong
たった今、アカデミーの副学長が、私が個人的に白仙洞にいると言いました。
This research has been done for several years
この研究は数年間にわたって行われてきました
So now it's almost certain
ということで、今ではほぼ確実です
The history of human habitation in Taiwan is now 30,000 years
台湾における人類の居住の歴史は現在3万年に及ぶ
At least 30,000 years at the latest
遅くても少なくとも3万年後
those 30,000 years
その3万年
Then let's make a comparison of Taiwan's history
それでは台湾の歴史を比較してみましょう
Then he only accounts for the written history of Taiwan?
では、彼は台湾の書かれた歴史だけを説明しているのでしょうか？
Only 1.3% of Taiwan's human history
台湾の人類の歴史のわずか 1.3%
So a little bit of the rest of the time is without text
残りの時間はテキストなしです
don't know
わかりません
unknown in the past
過去には知られていなかった
Later, archaeological data showed him
その後、考古学的データにより、彼は
If viewed on a mid-plane
ミッドプレーンで見た場合
Written History Accounts for Taiwan History
書かれた歴史が台湾の歴史を説明する
only 48 seconds
わずか48秒
Other such a big circle
他にもこんな大きなサークルが
basically no text
基本的にテキストはありません
so what if there is no text
では、テキストがなかったらどうなるでしょうか
must rely on archeology
考古学に頼らなければならない
So the vice president of archeology just mentioned
それで、考古学担当副学長が先ほど述べた
archeology is hard
考古学は難しい
to go to the fields to do cutting and digging
畑に行って掘る
Come back to organize, analyze, research
整理、分析、調査のために戻ってきてください
The purpose is to reconstruct the history of Taiwan
目的は台湾の歴史を再構築することです
Especially 99.0% of Taiwan
特に台湾の99.0%
This history needs to be borrowed from archeology
この歴史は考古学から借用する必要がある
information searched evidence searched
情報検索 証拠検索
Then come and help us rebuild
それから来て再建を手伝ってください
In addition, archaeological data
さらに、考古学的データ
Most of them are sold underground
ほとんどがアンダーグラウンドで販売されています
say to dig, to dig
掘る、掘ると言う
do fieldwork
フィールドワークをする
also in the water
水の中でも
submerged in water
水に浸かっている
So we inside the Taiwan Strait
それで私たちは台湾海峡の内側にいます
there are many flooded
浸水したものがたくさんあります
or silent these ancients
あるいは、この古代人たちを黙らせるか
transplant or transplant
移植か移植か
Well, this aspect actually needs to rely on Gu Xue's research.
まあ、この側面は実際にはGu Xueの研究に依存する必要があります。
So the vice president mentioned it just now. I personally also presided over an underwater valley team of our hospital recently.
それで、先ほど副院長からもお話がありましたが、私自身も最近、当院の水中バレーチームを主宰させていただきました。
So the purpose is around Taiwan
ということで目的は台湾周辺
Especially the Taiwan Strait or the South China Sea
特に台湾海峡や南シナ海
To do this underwater survey of these valleys
これらの渓谷の水中調査を行うには
Well, this is so relying on the Gu family to go to the field to find information
そうですね、これは顧家に頼って現場に行って情報を探すことです
So a lot of envy depends on the Gu family
妬みの多くは顧家に依存している
often travel outside
よく外に旅行する
Take a tour of the mountains and rivers, what about me personally?
山や川を巡るツアーに参加してみませんか。私個人はどうですか？
I don't know how to climb a mountain above the sea
海の上にある山にどうやって登ればいいのか分からない
It's all good, in fact, he doesn't know all kinds of hard work.
それは大丈夫です、実際、彼はあらゆる種類の苦労を知りません。
You only know if you have a bag
バッグを持っているかどうかだけがわかります
In addition, going to the sea is the same as going to Mizuno to investigate.
また、海に行くということは、水野に調査に行くのと同じことです。
So, therefore, whether these things are in the water
したがって、これらのものが水の中にあるかどうかは、
Or a space on land that can store these valley-based data?
それとも、これらの谷ベースのデータを保存できる陸上のスペースでしょうか?
basically become a size
基本的にサイズになります
It's just a transplant
ただの移植だよ
And what about these transplants, of course
もちろん、これらの移植についてはどうですか
We must rely on the research and analysis of Gu Xue
私たちはGu Xueの研究と分析に頼らなければなりません
What about after analyzing this research?
この研究を分析した後はどうでしょうか？
Only then can we make the incompleteness of human history
そうして初めて人類の歴史の不完全性を清算することができるのです
complement it
それを補完する
So Taiwan is facing 99.9% of Taiwan's history
つまり台湾は台湾の歴史の99.9%に直面していることになる
archaeological data
考古学的データ
the study of archaeology
考古学の研究
to supplement
サプリメントへ
to enrich
豊かにする
So therefore the archaeological site
したがって、遺跡は
It is a very important asset of a culture
それは文化の非常に重要な資産です
if you say don't pay attention to it
気にしないでと言ったら
that would easily destroy it
それは簡単に破壊してしまうだろう
so like this
だからこのように
Our current construction in various aspects in Taiwan
現在台​​湾で様々な面で工事を行っております
In fact, the ruins are constantly being destroyed.
実際、遺跡は絶えず破壊され続けています。
very many ruins
非常に多くの遺跡
This is a No. 13 ruins that I rescued in the past
こちらは以前救出したNo.13遺跡です
almost gone now
今はほとんどなくなっています
most are gone
ほとんどが消えてしまった
Like many ruins in Taiwan
台湾の多くの遺跡のように
Just like that, it was dug up by strange hands.
そのまま、見知らぬ手によって掘り起こされてしまいました。
once dug out
一度掘り出された
You can't rely on this anymore
もうこれに頼ることはできません
Let's recreate our past human history
過去の人類の歴史を再現しましょう
Of course now slowly
もちろん今はゆっくりと
our government
私たちの政府
our people
私たちの人々
also slowly understand
も徐々に理解していきます
These ruins should be protected
これらの遺跡は保護されるべきです
Now there are many means of protection
今では防御手段がたくさんあります
The first is through the law
1つ目は法律によるものです
Now currently we have a
現在、私たちは
Cultural Assets Preservation Act
文化財保存法
This law will require all engineering construction
この法律により、すべての工学的建設が義務付けられます
in the development process
開発過程で
or development must be done before
または開発はその前に行う必要があります
Always investigate and evaluate
常に調査して評価する
Then if it damages the chair
それで椅子が傷ついた場合には
so you have to go and that's it
だからあなたは行かなければなりません、それで終わりです
This project of yours needs to be adjusted
あなたのこのプロジェクトは調整する必要があります
or how to protect these chairs
またはこれらの椅子を保護する方法
The other is the Environmental Impact Assessment Act
もう一つは環境影響評価法です。
This law also clearly stipulates
この法律でも明確に定められています
all because of development
すべては開発のせい
adverse impact on the environment
環境への悪影響
environmental impact assessment
環境影響評価
This assessment also includes cultural and educational
この評価には文化的および教育も含まれます
or cultural facilities
または文化施設
or chair of culture
または文化委員長
In this way, if the development
このように発展すれば、
we can avoid
私たちは避けることができます
Destroy these chairs for development
開発のためにこれらの椅子を破壊してください
So therefore this archaeologist recently
それで、この考古学者は最近、
We especially know Taiwan's
私たちは特に台湾のことをよく知っています
In fact, there are not many people
実際は人もそんなに多くないし
We are a very small group
私たちは非常に小さなグループです
But we've taken on a pretty big job
しかし、私たちはかなり大きな仕事を引き受けました
Various developments in Taiwan now
台湾では今、様々な動きがあります
In fact, a lot of things have to be done
実際にはやらなければいけないことがたくさんある
do archaeological research
考古学的な研究をする
Do an archaeological assessment
考古学的評価を行う
like this one
このように
So many people joked that we said
とても多くの人が冗談を言いました。
Archaeologists in Taiwan are the fire brigade
台湾の考古学者は消防団だ
Why did the firefighters accuse the police of going to the fire?
なぜ消防士たちは警察が火事に行ったと非難したのですか?
Firefighting is not firefighting
消防は消防ではない
is to rescue or protect these ruins
これらの遺跡を救出または保護することです
then in general
それから一般的に
There are several ways to protect the site of this archaeological team
この考古学チームの遺跡を保護するにはいくつかの方法があります
The first one is that I just ask it to stop development
1つ目は、開発を中止するように要求することです
If the road or railway is going to pass by
道路や鉄道が通過しようとしている場合
sorry
ごめん
this site is very important
このサイトはとても重要です
very valuable
非常に価値のある
then you have to change your course
それならコースを変えなければなりません
Change the way you build
構築方法を変える
The second is to change the development content
2つ目は開発内容の変更です
That is to say, if this highway
つまり、この高速道路なら
to pass through this site
このサイトを通過するには
And this site is a very valuable site
そしてこのサイトはとても貴重なサイトです
after you remove it
それを削除した後
will have an impact on our entire history
私たちの歴史全体に影響を与えるだろう
I'm sorry
ごめんなさい
then you're going to change your
それならあなたは自分を変えるつもりです
But the project cannot be changed
ただしプロジェクトは変更できません
Building highways like Taiwan is difficult
台湾のような高速道路の建設は難しい
It's actually very difficult for you to make it change course
コースを変えるのは実際には非常に難しい
not only about economics
経済のことだけではなく
issues related to politics
政治に関連した問題
So this time I will ask
そこで今回質問させていただきます
You change the development content
開発内容を変更する
just change a way
ただ方法を変えるだけ
If this company can use high-priced bridge currency
この会社が高額なブリッジ通貨を使えるなら
Do not destroy this site
このサイトを破壊しないでください
these can look like this
これらは次のようになります
or one place one factory
または 1 か所 1 工場
I let you change its position
位置を変えさせてもらいました
keep it here
ここに置いておいてください
as a green space
緑地として
or for the park
または公園用
Then the third is finally no way
じゃあ3つ目はついに無理だな
Going to rescue and excavate
救助と発掘に行く
Connotation of unearthed sites
発掘現場の意味合い
to record
レコードする
to be unearthed
発掘される
this is a last resort
これは最後の手段です
Well like we are in Tainan Science Park
まるで台南サイエンスパークにいるようです
Today it is mainly called Nanke Archeology
現在は主に南渓考古学と呼ばれています。
Mainly refers to Tainan Science Park
主に台南サイエンスパークを指します。
Then this Tainan Branch
それからこの台南支店
we go
私たちは行く
The Nanke archaeological team of our aid institute
私たちの援助研究所の南渓考古学チーム
we are in the joint camp
私たちは共同キャンプ中です
15 years of field work
15年間のフィールドワーク
Every year is the soil of Seoul
毎年がソウルの土
struggle there
そこで奮闘する
then this part
それからこの部分
This is our picture
これが私たちの写真です
It's from Nanke
南渓からです
Currently we are in Nanke
現在南渓にいます。
a large number of ruins were found
大量の遺跡が発見された
In fact, the source of this work
実はこの作品の元ネタは
It's actually a very coincidental
実はとても偶然なんです
this accident
この事故
Because this was in the 81st year of the Republic of China
中華民国81年のことだから
Executive Yuan
行政院
It is to balance domestic
国内のバランスをとることです
technological development
技術開発
So it was decided to build a second science park in Tainan
そこで、台南に第二のサイエンスパークを建設することが決定されました。
The first one is Hsinchu Science Park
まずは新竹サイエンスパークです。
the second is in the south
2つ目は南にあります
Then choose its position at this time
次に、この時点での位置を選択します
Finally, the county in Tainan was selected.
最終的に台南県が選ばれた。
Tainan County
台南県
This Shanhua New City
この善華新城
And this place in the middle of the three townships of Anding
そしてこの場所は安定の3つの郷の真ん中にあります
This place was originally a farm in Taitang.
ここはもともと台唐の農場でした。
We know that many developments in Taiwan
台湾では多くの開発が行われていることを私たちは知っています
In the end, the land was found in Taitang
結局、台唐で土地が見つかった
Taitang is a big landlord
台唐は大地主です
So here is a big farm of Zhenong in Taitang
ここが台唐の鎮農の大きな農場です
So I chose this side as this
なのでこちら側をこれにしました
A base for Taiwan's second science park
台湾第二のサイエンスパークの拠点
what about this time
今回はどうですか
Of course it will cause a lot of problems
もちろん、それは多くの問題を引き起こすでしょう
There are many places to grab this position
このポジションを獲得できる場所はたくさんあります
So like the Lu tribe in Kaohsiung at that time
当時の高雄の魯族のように
they want
彼らは欲しい
Why Tainan and not Kaohsiung
なぜ高雄ではなく台南なのか
so we have to make noise
だから私たちは騒がなければなりません
The whole society has been making noise
社会全体が騒いでいる
and after
以降
The unit that disrupted the chaos at that time was the National Science Council
当時の混乱を打破した部隊は国家学術会議だった
The National Science Council will find me
国家学術会議が私を見つけてくれるでしょう
I wonder if there are any ruins here?
ここに遺跡があるのだろうか？
He said that he said that there are many ruins in the Lu nationality.
魯民族には遺跡が多いと言っていたそうです。
You can't develop, you will soon destroy the ruins
発展はできない、すぐに廃墟を破壊するだろう
Later I accepted his commission
その後私は彼の依頼を受け入れました
In 1984, a half-year investigation was conducted
1984年に半年間の調査が行われた
After investigation, it was found that
調査の結果、次のことが判明しました
Indeed there are ruins
確かに廃墟はある
So I gave the National Science Conference at that time
それで私は当時全国科学会議を開きました
At that time, the chairman of the committee was Guo Nanhong
当時の委員長は郭南紅氏だった。
Chairman Guo
郭会長
i gave the report
私は報告をしました
I said that there are not only ruins here
ここは遺跡だけじゃないって言った
And it's full of stars
そして星がいっぱいです
why?
なぜ？
because of this place
この場所のせいで
To the north is Zeng Wenxi, and over there is the Saltwater Creek
北側には曽文渓があり、反対側には塩水小川があります。
These two rivers are the most prone to flooding
これら 2 つの川は最も洪水が起こりやすいです
So this trouble in the past
それで、過去のこのトラブルは
If there is no driver to bother you, a lot of dirt will accumulate
ドライバーが邪魔しないとゴミがたくさん溜まる
so few leftovers from the past
過去の残り物はほとんどない
buried under the ground
地面の下に埋もれている
So the ground here
だからここの地面は
We reckon it's full of stars
星がいっぱいだと思うよ
dense like stars
星のように濃い
very relics
とても遺物
I said you will have problems in the future
将来的に問題が起きるだろうと言いました
development will encounter problems
開発には問題が発生します
what about the end
最後はどうですか
But the whole project has already started
しかし、プロジェクト全体はすでに始まっています
all booked
すべて予約済み
So in the end we got approval from the competent authority
それで最終的には管轄当局から承認を得ました
We've done a lot of
私たちはたくさんのことをしてきました
salvage excavation
サルベージ発掘
A small part is keeping it as an in situ reserve
ごく一部が原位置保護区として保管されています
Tainan Science Park
台南サイエンスパーク
I think everyone knows its location
誰もがその場所を知っていると思います
In Shanhua, in Xinshi, in Anding
善華、新市、安定
Probably its area is more than 1000 hectares
おそらくその面積は1000ヘクタール以上
That side is 1043 hectares
あちら側は1043ヘクタールです
This was used as a view of Taitang at that time.
これは当時の台唐の景色として使われていました。
You are dry on this farm
この農場ではあなたは乾いています
was desolate
荒涼としていた
that's totally different now
それは今は全く違います
Now it is a very modern science and technology park
現在は非常に近代的な科学技術パークになっています
Therefore, starting from the 1985 of the Republic of China
そこで中華民国の1985年から
we start the rescue
私たちは救助を開始します
Unexpectedly, it took more than ten years to rescue him once he was rescued.
意外なことに、一度救出されてから救出まで10年以上かかった。
Why
なぜ
Nanke continues to develop
発展を続ける南科
Then there are transplants
あとは移植とか
Then why? Because the sky is full of stars
ではなぜ? 空には星がいっぱいだから
Stars in the sky basement transplant
天空の星 地下室移植
So we have been developing
そこで私たちは開発を進めてきました
just keep discovering
ただ発見し続けるだけ
keep discovering and then have to deal with
発見し続け、その後対処しなければならない
After treatment, we must do rescue
治療後は救出をしなければなりません
So we can see as
したがって、次のように見ることができます
We have five stages of rescue
救助には5つの段階があります
From the 1984 of the Republic of China is the first stage
1984年から中華民国が第一段階となる
Then the second one is 85 years
2番目は85年です
The third stage is 92 years
第三段階は92年
The fourth stage is 94 years
第4段階は94年
Now it's 94 to 99
今は94対99です
Then, five stages of rescue work were done.
その後、5段階の救出作業​​が行われた。
Then what we salvage is a large-scale excavation
では、私たちがサルベージするのは大規模な発掘調査です
As a look at this, what we move one by one is the exploration pit we excavated.
これを見てみますと、一つずつ移動させていくのが掘削した探査坑です。
As a look at our chairs, each chair is made on a large scale
私たちの椅子はどれも大型に作られているので、
Excavate as many toys as possible from the ground
地面からできるだけ多くのおもちゃを掘り出す
in a very systematic record
非常に体系的な記録の中で
As a matter of fact, each excavation is such a large-scale excavation.
実際、毎回の発掘はこれほど大規模な発掘です。
are very large
とても大きいです
Then we dig the rest at night
それから夜に残りを掘ります
Because sometimes when he is constructing
なぜなら、彼が建築しているとき、時々、
must be in a hurry
急いでいるに違いない
This is our factory building in Qimei’s Qimei
これは七美の七美にある私たちの工場の建物です
because he said they already took the order
なぜなら、彼はすでに注文を受け付けていると言っていたからです
If he does not start work for a day, the factory will not be completed and work will not start
一日仕事を始めないと工場は完成せず、仕事も始まらない
his loss is a terrible loss
彼の喪失はひどい喪失だ
So what about this matter?
それで、この件についてはどうですか？
And at the same time, the room is already under construction and all the machines are ready.
同時に、部屋はすでに建設中であり、すべての機械の準備が整っています。
So we have to do it within 45 days
だから45日以内にやらなければならない
think about these chairs
これらの椅子について考えてください
This is what a staff member does
スタッフの仕事はこんな感じ
are local farmers
地元の農家です
Then we became each very experienced archaeologists
それから私たちはそれぞれ非常に経験豊富な考古学者になりました
This one is that we and my staff were only four people
これは、私たちと私のスタッフはたったの4人でした
Finally we got to a few years later
ついに数年後にたどり着きました
become such a large and huge team
こんなに大きくて巨大なチームになる
That's what everyone does now
それは今誰もがやっていることです
Actually they really like working for us
実際、彼らは私たちのために働くのがとても好きです
why?
なぜ？
Originally they were farmers from nearby villages
もともと彼らは近くの村の農民でした
Later, their land was confiscated because of the Science Park.
その後、サイエンスパークのせいで彼らの土地は没収されました。
They don't work anymore
彼らはもう機能しません
so we just happen to have jobs
だから私たちにはたまたま仕事があるだけ
he has joined us
彼は私たちに加わりました
Still interested in doing this
まだこれに興味があります
It makes sense to do this
これを行うのは理にかなっています
So we went through 15 years of field work
そこで私たちは15年間のフィールドワークを経験しました
We have about 50 vents in total
通気口は全部で50個くらいあります
Later, it gradually increased to more than 80 ruins
その後、徐々に増えて80以上の遺跡になりました
34 of them
そのうち34人
We have extensively excavated
幅広く発掘してきました
So just now Fu Yuanyang mentioned
それで今、傅元洋が言いました。
We have released several million pieces of these cultural relics in the future
私たちはこれらの文化的遺物を今後数百万点に渡って公開していきます。
we are not in the warehouse
私たちは倉庫にいません
still need one by one
まだ一つずつ必要です
to be organized
整理される
Only then can this history be recreated
そうして初めてこの歴史を再現することができる
Rediscover it from these materials
資料から再発見する
So this is a support that we have also become the Ministry of Science and Technology.
ですから、これは科学技術省としても支援しているわけです。
We are currently continuing to nine years
現在9年目まで継続中です
Continuously analyzing these cultural relics
これらの文化遺物を継続的に分析する
Rescue us also works with some technology
Rescue us は一部のテクノロジーでも機能します
We are like the ones in the hospital, we are like the new cloud doctor, and the doctor is also present
私たちは病院にいる​​人々のようなものであり、新しいクラウドドクターのようなものであり、医師もそこにいます
We he both do analysis of the millet of these rice plants
私たち彼は二人ともこれらの稲のキビの分析をしています
There are also some medical analysis, etc.
医学的な分析などもあります。
We still do these parts
私たちはまだこれらの部分を行っています
But from inside
でも少しずつ
We slowly put at least the 5,000-year history of Nanke in Taiwan
少なくとも5000年の歴史を南柯にゆっくりと込めていきます
can build it up
それを構築することができます
At this time we are in Nanke as a watch
只今南柯に監視中です
All of these found in each of these ruins
これらはすべてこれらの遺跡のそれぞれで見つかりました
Then there are some ruins that are salvaged on a large scale
その後、大規模に回収された遺跡がいくつかあります
massive excavation
大規模な発掘
These guys have played a lot
この人たちはたくさん遊んだよ
Naughty, Stone, Jade, Bone, Iron, Bronze, etc.
いたずら、石、翡翠、骨、鉄、青銅など。
At the same time, we also found more than 2,000 wooden sticks
同時に2,000本以上の木の棒も発見されました。
It means that there are more than 2,000 human bones
人骨は2,000以上あるということです
This human bone is based on osteology
この人間の骨は骨学に基づいています
this is very very important
これはとてもとても重要です
It not only provides an understanding of the human body in the past
過去の人体の理解を提供するだけではありません
and disease
そして病気
But the composition of the population etc.
ただ、人口構成などは
can provide some very important information
非常に重要な情報を提供できる
so now we are a
だから今私たちは
About the cultural relics found in Nanke
南柯で発見された文化財について
can be summed up
要約できる
Can help it have ten culture periods
10回の培養期間を持つのに役立ちます
The earliest is five thousand years
最も早いものは5000年前
about four thousand eight
約4,800
up to five thousand
5000まで
The latest one below can arrive
最新のものは以下から到着可能です
Han people in the early Ming and Qing Dynasties
明清初期の漢民族
So overall we differentiate into
したがって、全体的には次のように区別されます
Divided into ten cultural wonders
10の文化的驚異に分けられる
In every miracle
あらゆる奇跡の中で
have a very rich content of these
これらのコンテンツが非常に豊富です
Then inside each content
次に、各コンテンツ内で
can tell us
私たちに教えてください
a lot of history about the past
過去についてのたくさんの歴史
So this is what I want today below
というわけで今日は以下の内容にしたいと思います
Dr Li Fangji
李框季博士
for each culture period
文化期ごとに
like found inside
中で見つかったような
and how do we analyze
そしてどのように分析するのか
doing research?
調査する？
to give you a report
報告をするために
I'm having a hard time
大変です
give you an introduction
紹介してください
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
next one
次の
Thank you Vice President Wang
王副社長に感謝します
He came to Nanke twice during his tenure
彼は在任中に二度南柯に来た
So this is a big thank you for his support and encouragement.
ですから、彼のサポートと励ましにとても感謝しています。
So this can have today
それで今日はこれでいいのです
he contributed
彼は貢献した
This is good
これはいい
Then I will follow in the footsteps of Mr. Zhang
それから私は張さんの足跡をたどります
This Nanke archaeological discovery in Taiwan for 5,000 years
台湾で5000年にわたる南柯遺跡の発見
In fact I want to tell you
実はあなたに伝えたいのですが
Just now Mr. Zhang told me to remove this one
たった今、張さんにこれを削除するように言われました
I said without your medal
メダルなしで言った
in fact one of each
実際にはそれぞれ1つずつ
He has his medal and I have one of mine
彼は彼のメダルを持っており、私は私のメダルを持っています
But what about the one on the side and the one on the right?
しかし、横のものと右側のものはどうでしょうか？
only one
唯一
Seems
らしい
What about this one?
これはどうですか？
This is what really explains the content of our award.
これがまさに私たちの賞の内容を説明するものです。
Well, of course, if it wasn't for this one
まあ、もちろん、これがなかったら
Of course, there seems to be no chance to stand here today.
もちろん、今日ここに立つチャンスはなさそうだ。
This is indeed the case
まさにその通りです
First of all, let me explain to you
まず初めに説明させていただきますが、
I should have no chance
チャンスなんてないはずなのに
But what about an opportunity like this?
しかし、このような機会はどうでしょうか？
Special thanks to Academician Zhang
張学術研究員に感謝します
Academician Zhang didn’t just bring me into Academia Sinica
張学者は私を中央研究院に連れて行ってくれただけではありません
Even I was able to go to Nanke because of him
私も彼のおかげで南柯に行けました
1987 Separate Go
1987年 セパレートゴー
His Separate Go, he went to England
彼は別居してイギリスへ行った
He told me before you left
あなたが出発する前に彼は私に言いました
Come and help me lead this project of Nanke
南科のこのプロジェクトを指揮するのを手伝ってください
Then I said how do I bring a plan?
それから私は、どうやって計画を立てればよいのか、と言いました。
He said you don't need a plan
彼は計画なんて必要ないって言った
This already has our team over there
これにはすでに私たちのチームがいます
In fact, this leadership of my program for that year
実際、その年の私のプログラムのリーダーシップは、
It's not called a leader, it's actually called a cup of NTD from Nangang to Tainan
これはリーダーとは呼ばれず、実際には南港から台南までのNTDのカップと呼ばれています
I got this kind of treatment very generously
とても丁寧な対応をしていただきました
Yes as soon as they see me arriving they know I have money
はい、彼らは私が到着するのを見るとすぐに、私がお金を持っていることを知りました
Because at that time I was the one who took the check and went to the Farmer's Bank to collect NT dollars
なぜなら当時、小切手を受け取って農民銀行に台湾ドルを受け取りに行ったのは私だったからです。
Then I packed it in the bag with the camera
それからカメラと一緒にバッグに詰めました
Then when they got on the plane they thought it was a camera
そして飛行機に乗ったとき、彼らはそれがカメラだと思った
But I also know they probably know what's in there
でも、彼らはそこに何が入っているかをおそらく知っていることも私は知っています
It's not a camera, because the shadow of a camera is different
カメラじゃないよ、カメラの影が違うから
Then I should say that if there is not such a chance
じゃあ、そんなチャンスがなかったら言ってみようかな
Then it is not because of this distribution of Nanke archaeological sites
それでは、南柯遺跡のこの分布のせいではない
So I have seen what Mr. Zhang said
張氏の言ったことはわかりました
What is more important is a distribution like this
より重要なのは、このような分布です
This completely subverts the cognition of Taiwan's archaeological circles
これは台湾の考古学界の認識を完全に覆すものである
Frankly speaking, before the 1995 Republic of China
率直に言って、1995年の中華民国以前は
Not before 1995 in 1995
1995 年以前ではない 1995 年
No ruins have ever been found in this park.
この公園では遺跡は見つかっていません。
I used to follow Mr. Zhang
私は張さんをフォローしていました
Let's go to the outer ring road of Naner Gao
ナネルガオの外環状道路へ行こう
The middle of the outer ring road is relatively close
外環道の真ん中が比較的近い
A site called Kanxi
Kanxi というサイト
on the periphery of the park
公園の外れで
In other words, the entire park
つまり、公園全体が
Among the more than 70 ruins discovered so far
これまでに発見された70以上の遺跡の中から
Didn't know any before 1995
1995年以前は何も知らなかった
So at a mileage like this
それでこのくらいの走行距離で
This archaeological excavation work in the entire Nanke Park
南柯公園全体を対象とした遺跡発掘作業
Transformed Taiwan's archaeological circles
変容した台湾の考古学界
In particular what we call contract archeology
特に私たちが契約考古学と呼ぶもの
such a mission
そんなミッション
Also found so many of these ruins
こういった遺跡もたくさん見つかりました
So these decades
それでこの数十年間
I frankly say that I am half a Taipei native
正直に言うと、私は半分台北人です
I started on July 1, 2007
2007 年 7 月 1 日に始めました
I have two to three days a week
週に2〜3日あります
lived in Tainan
台南に住んでいました
So I think a ban like this
だからこのような禁止はあると思う
give me a lot of this opportunity
このような機会をたくさん与えてください
not just academically
学業面だけでなく
in work management
作業管理において
The whole thing got me a lot of these
全体として、これらをたくさん手に入れました
accumulation of experience
経験の蓄積
In fact, I can also take this opportunity
実は私もこの機会に利用できます
Come to the courtyard, come to the office
中庭に来て、オフィスに来てください
even in my own home
自分の家でも
to illustrate over the years
長年にわたって説明する
I'm such a crackpot
私はとてもクズです
or
また
The high-speed rail should give me some briefings, right?
高速鉄道は私に説明をしてくれるはずですよね？
good
良い
Speaking of which, I still want to give you an idea first.
そういえば、やはり最初にアイデアをお伝えしたいと思います。
That is to say, the so-called 5,000 years of Taiwan mentioned earlier
つまり、先ほど述べた、いわゆる台湾の5000年です。
Taiwan's 5,000-year history
台湾5000年の歴史
Mr. Zhang mentioned it to you at the beginning
張さんは冒頭でそれについて話しましたね
The United people said that Taiwan originally had no history
米国人は台湾にはもともと歴史がなかったと述べた
There is only 400 years of history from the Henan people
河南民族の歴史はわずか400年
But here we want to talk to you
しかし、ここで私たちはあなたに話したいのです
We have literally five thousand years of history
私たちには文字通り5000年の歴史があります
what about this
これはどうですか
or so he said
あるいはそう彼は言いました
If you want to convey a concept like this to
こんなコンセプトを伝えたいなら
He already had some knowledge of Taiwan's history
彼はすでに台湾の歴史についてある程度の知識を持っていました
He already told you to lie
彼はすでにあなたに嘘をつくように言いました
but the fact is not
しかし事実はそうではありません
From the accumulations inside the archaeological site, we
遺跡内の蓄積物から、
I can tell you
教えられます
The Nanke Archaeological Site Group has accumulated
南柯遺跡群が蓄積してきた
Some history of Taiwan over the past 5,000 years
過去5,000年にわたる台湾の歴史
so many years
何年も
We found more than 2,000 of these sticks
この棒が 2,000 本以上見つかりました
I'm not going to lie to you
あなたに嘘をつくつもりはありません
I often tell a lot of people in society
私は社会の多くの人によく言います。
Wherever I go, maybe half of them will follow me
私がどこへ行っても、そのうちの半分は私についてくるかもしれません
Maybe you're next door
もしかしたらあなたは隣にいるかもしれません
And those who followed you next to each other
そして隣り合ってあなたをフォローした人たち
This is what I told the Nanke Park Administration
これは私が南科公園管理局に伝えたことです
I said I have been so ten years
私はもう10年も経ったと言いました
What you see is fantasy
あなたが見ているものはファンタジーです
But more than 2,000 of these from 5,000 to 300 years
しかし、そのうち 2,000 個以上は 5,000 年から 300 年の間に
What about these grain trees in the past few years?
ここ数年の木目はどうでしょうか？
Their souls have been running on it
彼らの魂はその上を走っている
I even sometimes
私も時々
I wish I could tell them
彼らに伝えられたらいいのに
The roof of your building is very black
あなたの建物の屋根はとても黒いです
then you'll know what that is
そうすればそれが何なのか分かるでしょう
ok that
わかりました、それは
In fact, one of the biggest benefits of
実際、最大の利点の 1 つは、
what we found
私たちが見つけたもの
It's not just that there are many chairs, it's the same thing
椅子が多いだけじゃなくて同じこと
it is in very good condition
とても良い状態です
It seems that we can clearly
明らかにできるようです
to find its source
その源を見つけるために
its long
それは長い
its time complete
時間は完了しました
Even we have a lot of
私たちにもたくさんあります
these kinds of diversity
こういった多様性
So it seems that what I want to tell you
それで、私があなたに伝えたいことは、
From some clusters of chairs that look like this
こんな感じの椅子の群から
we are talking about environmental change
私たちは環境の変化について話しています
let's talk about ecological adaptation
生態適応について話しましょう
We talk about social structures , we talk about living crafts and technologies
私たちは社会構造について話し、生きた工芸品やテクノロジーについて話します
Even when we talk about life should be and faith, etc.
人生がどうあるべきか、信仰などについて話すときも。
These issues are what give us the opportunity to get to know Taiwan
これらの問題は私たちに台湾を知る機会を与えてくれます
I have known Taiwan for so many years
私は台湾を長年知っています
How are these people living here?
この人たちはここでどうやって暮らしているのですか？
Just now Mr. Zhang also mentioned
今、張氏も言及しました
Taiwan has been inhabited here since 30,000 years ago
台湾には3万年前から人が住んでいた
But inside a pair of glasses at such a time
でもそんな時メガネの中では
From the old era to the new era
古い時代から新しい時代へ
to the Iron Age to the early Han Chinese
鉄器時代から漢民族の初期まで
when you come here
君が来る時
In fact, we still have a lot of gaps that we don't understand clearly
実際には、まだ明確に理解していないギャップがたくさんあります
in other words
言い換えると
tell you
教えてください
I specially drew a red circle here
ここに特別に赤い丸を描きました
sorry
ごめん
If this is in your history textbook
これが歴史の教科書に載っていたら
there will be a witness
証人がいるだろう
The witness also claimed to have a time of 30,000 years ago
目撃者は3万年前の時代もあったと主張した
But recently
でも最近
One of our colleagues was originally a student of mine
私たちの同僚の一人はもともと私の生徒でした
Teacher at Tsinghua University
清華大学教師
As a result, only three thousand years were withdrawn as witnesses.
その結果、証人として撤回されたのはわずか3000年だけだった
Originally, Mayor Lai wanted to take that specimen back.
当初、ライ市長はその標本を持ち帰ろうとしていました。
I think now he doesn't want it either
今は彼もそれを望んでいないのだと思います
good
良い
Another fact I want to mention to you is that
もう一つお話しておきたい事実は、
From the Changbing Culture 30,000 years ago
3万年前の長平文化より
until the new period we now know
私たちが今知っている新しい時代まで
Early Age Crash
初期の時代のクレーター
We have no specific archaeological accumulations in this period
この時代には特別な考古学的蓄積物はありません
This also shows that this group of people in the early days of the new era
これはまた、このグループが新しい時代の初期にあったことを示しています。
Not this group of people from Changbing culture
長平文化のこのグループの人々ではありません
a continuation of life
人生の継続
This continuation of life comes from
この生命の継続は、
Under such an understanding
そのような理解の下で
i want to tell you
私はあなたに伝えたいです
When did Taiwan become Taiwan?
台湾はいつから台湾になったのですか?
this question is difficult to answer
この質問は答えるのが難しいです
Did someone say you were talking about politics?
誰かがあなたが政治について話していると言いましたか？
I don't hide from you
私はあなたから隠れません
I was once inside the opportunity where the minister of culture led a group of journalists
私はかつて、文化大臣がジャーナリストのグループを率いている場にいたことがあります。
I asked them the same question
私は彼らに同じ質問をしました
Some say tens of millions of years, millions of years
何千万年、何百万年とも言う人もいます
I said when did Taiwan leave a connection with mainland China
私は、台湾はいつ中国本土とのつながりをやめたのかと言いました。
Many people are stupid over there
あそこはバカが多いよ
18,000 years ago, Taiwan could still use roads and bridges to walk
1万8000年前、台湾はまだ道路や橋を使って歩くことができた
Arrive in mainland China
中国本土に到着
But in fact by 8000 years
しかし実際には8000年までに
The Taiwan Strait has been formed
台湾海峡が形成されました
If this understanding is correct when
この理解が正しければ、
After 8000 years, there is no such fact that 8000 years have come to Taiwan
8000年を経て台湾に8000年が来たという事実はない
archaeological evidence
考古学的証拠
In the early days of the New Reality Era, within our 5,6000 years
新現実時代の初期、56000年以内
what must this group of people be like
この人々のグループはどのようなものでなければなりませんか
Is it enough
それは十分か
slipping slipping slipping boat
滑る 滑る 滑る ボート
Otherwise, it's swimming
そうでなければ水泳です
In fact it is impossible
実際にはそれは不可能です
In such an understanding
そのような理解の中で
Let's look back at our Nanke Yuan District
南柯園区を振り返ってみましょう
In this more than 2000 hectares
この2000ヘクタール以上の土地で
stacked inside
中に積み上げられた
It also provides some process of our whole environment change
また、私たちの環境全体の変化のプロセスも提供します
I want to tell you
私はあなたに伝えたいです
This is what Mr. Zhang just mentioned
これは張氏が先ほど言ったことです
Nanke in 1995
1995年の南科
yes
はい
Cemetery
お墓
Inano Cemetery
稲野霊園
Inano Farm
稲野農園
The whole thing is so dry
全体がとても乾いています
There is another western orifice
もう一つ西側の開口部があります
because they are burden bearers
彼らは重荷を負う者だから
so
それで
A lot of chairs never get a chance to be flipped open first
多くの椅子は最初にひっくり返して開く機会がありません
Because you planted this is only a shallow root, forty or fifty centimeters
あなたが植えたので、これは40センチか50センチの浅い根だけです
they can just plant
彼らはただ植えることができる
Well, Nanke in 2012 is a sight like this
さて、2012年の南柯はこんな光景です
you can imagine
想像できるでしょう
A change in the environment of the entire southwestern coast of Taiwan
台湾南西海岸全体の環境変化
what will it be like
それはどうなるでしょうか
When I was really straight
本当に真っ直ぐだった頃
Some people even say that it is impossible to find the ruins in this place
この場所に遺跡を見つけるのは不可能だとさえ言う人もいます
Why?
なぜ？
Because it was originally in a water environment
もともと水環境にあったため
This understanding is not bad
この理解は悪くない
If you look at this map
この地図を見ると
This is a map of city descendants, an elevated map of city descendants
これは都市の子孫の地図、都市の子孫の高度な地図です
At certain times the entire park is
時間によっては公園全体が
Still in the water environment
まだ水環境にある
We make from many places
いろいろなところから作っています
Taiwan restrictions Many restrictions
台湾の制限 制限が多い
can be found
見つけることができます
They also had records saying
という記録も残っていた。
The whole big ship can go all the way here
大きな船は丸ごとここまで行ける
In a location where the so-called Newport is located
いわゆるニューポートがある場所
Okay, this is what Mr. Zhang just showed to everyone
さて、これが張さんが今みんなに見せたものです
Our Sanjin is still doing it in the middle of the night
我らの三神は今も真夜中にやってる
Not called Sanjin Midnight
三人ミッドナイトとは呼ばれない
In fact at that time
実はその時は
do it from 7:30 in the morning
朝7時半からやる
until half past ten in the evening
夕方10時半まで
Chi Mei, but it's not called Chi Mei anymore
チーメイですが、もうチーメイとは呼ばれません
This is what happened
これが起こったのです
Innolux
イノラックス
they asked us
彼らは私たちに尋ねました
It means a loss of 100 million a day
つまり1日あたり1億円の損失になる
if we can afford it
余裕があれば
But archeology can have 100 million
しかし、考古学には1億の情報が存在する可能性があります
I think maybe Mr. Zhang also has a clue.
もしかしたら張さんにもヒントがあるのではないかと思います。
he sold several
彼はいくつか売りました
can't sell the house
家が売れない
good
良い
This is the current surface
これが現在の表面です
what about this ruins
この遺跡はどうですか
In this way, there are seven meters
このようにして7メートルあります
everybody
みんな
you can then
そうすればできます
when we were doing exploration
私たちが探検をしていたとき
you can find
発見できる
such a deep pile
こんなに深い山
in other words
言い換えると
five thousand years
五千年
Its a stack of seven meters
7メートルの積み重ねです
If a change in the entire geographical environment
地理的環境全体が変化した場合
such a data
そのようなデータ
The data is also very fast
データもとても速いです
we follow
私たちはフォローする
One of Mr. Chen Wenshan's
陳文山氏の作品の一つ
Under the synergy
相乗効果のもとで
He made a transfer of the entire address
彼は住所全体を移転した
Judgment and Restoration of the Coastline
海岸線の審判と修復
That let us also find out
それは私たちも調べましょう
A location where the entire circle is located
円全体が位置する場所
would happen to be near a coastline where it was 5,000 years ago
偶然にも5000年前の海岸線の近くにあっただろう
So we can clearly understand
それで私たちははっきりと理解することができます
From a change in the entire coastal environment
沿岸全体の環境の変化から
until 6000 years ago
6000年前までは
The entire Nanke Park is still in the water
南柯公園全体がまだ水の中にあります
By the year 5000 we started to enter
5000年までに私たちは参入し始めました
Just now Mr. Zhang also explained
先ほど張さんも説明してくれました。
Because there is Zeng Wenxi in the north and Yanshuixi in the south
北には曽文渓、南には塩水渓があるので
There is a river shortfall on the west coast of Taiwan
台湾の西海岸では川が不足しています
and when it rains
そして雨が降ったら
It can bring a large amount of sediment to accumulate very quickly
大量の沈殿物が急速に蓄積する可能性があります
in fact here
実はここで
I also want to share with you a piece of news like this
また、こんなニュースもお伝えしたいと思います
what commonday magazine did
コモンデイ誌が何をしたのか
You know what problem we are facing now
私たちが今どんな問題に直面しているか知っていますか
Global warming, this is a fact, a geologist in Australia in 1993, what he did would cause a sea level rise of three centimeters every year
地球温暖化、これは事実です、1993年オーストラリアの地質学者、彼のやったことは毎年3センチメートルの海面上昇を引き起こすでしょう
If you start with a count rate like this, if you flood 6 meters, 15 meters, 25 meters, everyone knows that this is a balance
このようなカウント率から始めると、6 メートル、15 メートル、25 メートルに浸水した場合、これがバランスであることは誰もが知っています。
If you have a sense of crisis when you see this, I will show you this again
これを見て危機感を持ったらもう一度見せます
In 2080, Wonsan Hotel, probably I know that when you go out, the second thing is to call Wonsan Hotel immediately, if there is any space above the tenth floor, you can just buy it
2080年、元山ホテル、おそらく私は知っています、外出するときはすぐに元山ホテルに電話してください、10階以上のスペースがあればそのまま購入できます
It was 2080, Wonsan Hotel probably knew the current situation, now it is 2080, Wonsan Hotel probably knew the current situation, you can just buy
それは2080年でした、元山ホテルはおそらく現状を知っていました、今は2080年です、元山ホテルはおそらく現状を知っていました、あなたはただ買うことができます
2010 101
2010年的101
of course i will say
もちろん言います
In 2080
2080年
i'm on the mountain behind
私は裏の山にいる
wave with everyone
みんなで手を振る
good
良い
then this is one
それならこれが1つです
environmental change
環境の変化
a difference in rate
レートの違い
everybody
みんな
one like this
このようなもの
under the concept
コンセプトのもとに
Let's see Nanke
南渓を見てみよう
Nanke for so many years
長年ナンケ
let us
私たちにさせて
know
知る
From 5000 until
5000から
Late entry
レイトエントリー
Two or three hundred years
二百年か三百年か
even
平
we can see
見える
the last 20 years
過去20年間
all the whole
全部全部
a change in the environment
環境の変化
people coming and going
行き交う人々
what did we see
私たちは何を見たのか
5000 years ago
5000年前
I want to give you
あなたにあげたい
look first
まず見てください
Naughty Supply's Technology
Naughty Supplyのテクノロジー
a change of
の変化
Everyone too
みんなも
if you have a concept
コンセプトがあるなら
you can all understand
皆さんは理解できます
In the early century era Dabunkeng culture was fascinated by Wentao
世紀初頭の大文坑文化は文陶に魅了された
One of their trances Wen Tao
彼らのトランス状態の1人、ウェンタオ
It is just a feature of the appearance and shape of a whole pottery
あくまで陶器全体の見た目や形の特徴です。
actually real content
実際に本物のコンテンツ
one of its appearance
その姿の一つ
how does it do
それはどうですか
What kind of soil is it made of?
どのような土でできているのでしょうか？
What kind of technology was used to develop it?
開発にはどのような技術が使われたのでしょうか？
This is what we really want to understand
これが私たちが本当に理解したいことです
You can also see a variety of
などもご覧いただけます
Except for the god Wentao
ウェンタオ神を除いて
its shape
その形
this is a bean
これは豆です
This is Chai Tao
チャイタオです
This chai pottery is not the most primitive and recognized one
このチャイ陶器は最も原始的で認識されているものではありません
one of the cultural characteristics
文化的特徴の一つ
Even from an element like this, we can
このような要素からも、
to understand the inner relationship of its culture
その文化の内的関係を理解する
this is a gas cap
これはガスキャップです
This is covered by a shell of blood and sweat
血と汗の殻で覆われている
Remember Academician Zhang Guangze
学者の張光沢氏を思い出してください
A theory put forward by Academician Zhang Guangze
学者の張光沢氏が提唱した理論
He from a decorative document like this
彼はこのような装飾的な文書から
To illustrate the top of the Phu Quocton ruins in Kinmen
金門のフーコックトン遺跡の頂上を説明する
He also explained the same
彼も同じことを説明してくれました
This may have a relationship above the Culture class circle relationship
これは、文化クラスのサークル関係を超える関係がある可能性があります
Well, four thousand years ago
さて、四千年前
Guys, on our archaeological culture
皆さん、私たちの考古学文化について
We call it Xishen Wentao
私たちはそれを西深文道と呼んでいます
Or call it Shenwen red pottery culture
あるいは、神文赤陶文化と呼ぶこともあります。
but you can find out
しかし、あなたは知ることができます
The whole appearance situation has changed
全体の出現状況が変わりました
We even found four sticks
棒も4本見つかりました
We call it "Hongguan"
私たちはそれを「紅関」と呼びます
Here is the child's body
こちらがその子の遺体です
children's shares
子供の株
inside
中身
This is also the earliest in Taiwan
これも台湾で一番早いです
A record of this "Hongguan"
この「紅関」の記録
We can even see a variety of
さまざまなものも見ることができます
But you obviously you can find out
でも明らかに分かるよ
It is the same as the 5000 years ago
5000年前と同じだ
are different
異なっています
good
良い
this is an escape
これは逃げです
Also stated let us know they made the escape themselves
また、彼らが自ら脱出したことを知らせるとも述べられています
A legacy of such a tool
このようなツールの遺産
The Great Lakes culture to 3000 years ago
3000年前までの五大湖の文化
You can see it right away
すぐに見れますよ
it's black
黒い
so red hot red
とても真っ赤で真っ赤
This technique changes to slightly horizontal black
このテクニックはやや横長の黒に変化します
Then how do you think about it?
では、どう考えますか？
it's a group of people
それは人々のグループです
A different group of people came here
別のグループの人がここに来ました
What makes us depressed is how come
私たちを落ち込ませるのはなぜですか
why come
なぜ来るのか
Until the Iron Age 2000 years ago
2000年前の鉄器時代まで
What kind of red color has the whole process technology changed into?
プロセス技術全体がどのような赤色に変化したのでしょうか？
And you can find out
そして、あなたは知ることができます
Is it one of their crafting techniques?
それも彼らの製作技術の一つなのでしょうか？
has slowly declined
徐々に衰退してきました
What a change
なんという変化でしょう
red to black
赤から黒へ
black to red
黒から赤へ
Even the whole appearance is different.
全体の見た目も違います。
This is even the gas cap you can find, the same as the gas cap from 5,000 years ago
これは、5,000年前のガスキャップと同じものです。
The air cap from 5,000 years ago is inside our life now
5,000年前のエアキャップが今、私たちの生活の中にあります
can also see the very common air-shaped
非常に一般的な空気の形も見ることができます
We can even find that as far as the Iron Age
鉄器時代に至るまでそれを見つけることができます
A gaseous shape characteristic of the symbol of this puppet
この人形のシンボルに特徴的なガス状の形状
More than 500 years ago, we thought it belonged to
500年以上前、私たちはそれが次のものであると考えていました。
Inside a legacy of Hirayan culture
ヒラヤン文化の遺産の内部
The most important thing is that they still retain the iron age
最も重要なことは、鉄器時代と同じ状態を保っていることです。
The making of soft pottery of Niaosong culture
ニャオソン文化の柔らかな陶器づくり
At the same time they also have a lot of these from mainland China
同時に、中国本土からのものもたくさんあります
There are also some from Southeast Asia
東南アジアからのものもある
There is also this one from Kyushu Feitian, Japan
日本の九州飛天産のものもあります
One of these mischievous remnants of shaker making
シェーカー作りのいたずらな残骸の 1 つ
These are all explained
これらはすべて説明されています
These people who live in Tainan at the same time
同じ時代に台南に住んでいる人たち
How are you from other places?
他の場所からはどうですか？
interact with one of their living environments
彼らの生活環境の一つと対話する
The evidence that remains
残る証拠
Well, these people from 5,000 years ago
さて、これらの人々は5000年前からいます
let us know
我々に教えてください
They are likely to be heavily dependent on
彼らは次のものに大きく依存している可能性が高い
marine resources food resources
海洋資源 食料資源
Why because from what remains of our animal bones
なぜかというと、私たちの動物の骨が残っているからです。
We found that there are a large number of
多数存在することが分かりました。
These numbers of boruids exceed those of land-based
これらのボロイドの数は陸上のボロイドの数を上回ります
what remains of these fish
この魚の残り物は何ですか
in our knowledge
私たちの知識では
We found three different species of these cartilaginous fish
これらの軟骨魚の 3 つの異なる種を発見しました。
For example, a shark's, a fish's, a bite, a giant bite
例: サメ、魚、一口、巨大な一口
Nineteen species of bony fishes
19 種の硬骨魚
These are actually us
これらは実際には私たちです
make real professional
本当のプロフェッショナルになる
helped us identify
特定するのに役立ちました
for example this
たとえばこれ
This is in our earliest cognition
これは私たちの初期の認識では
Thought it was going to be this head of an amphibian
両生類の頭かと思った
Turns out it was a shark
それはサメだったことが判明
This is this fish near the mouth of the river
これは河口近くにいた魚です
This is what we found out last year
これは昨年判明したことです
We first called it mangosteen
最初はマンゴスチンと呼んでいました
i traveled all over europe
私はヨーロッパ中を旅行しました
Go to France, to Germany, to Japan, to the United States to ask what this is
フランス、ドイツ、日本、アメリカに行って、これが何なのか尋ねてください。
As a result no one can recognize
結果として誰も認識できなくなる
We even got the University of York in the UK to do puthi for us
英国のヨーク大学にもプーシをやってもらいました
But the analysis of white matter seems to want to know what the animal would look like
しかし、白質の分析では、その動物がどのように見えるかを知りたいようです
It turned out that last year an assistant at the Museum of Marine Biology
昨年、海洋生物学博物館の助手だったことが判明した
He went to Belgium to study his doctorate
彼は博士号を学ぶためにベルギーに行きました
He told us that this is a monitoring department in Huiqingjiao
彼はここが匯青角市の監視部門だと言いました。
Everyone, this animal was beaten by humans
皆さん、この動物は人間に殴られたのです
In other words, after they hit these fish
つまり、これらの魚をヒットさせた後、
They also used one of his supervisory news departments as a supervisory news department
彼らはまた、彼の監督報道部門の1つを監督報道部門として使用した
a decoration to use
使用する装飾品
good
良い
except fish
魚を除いて
they use a lot
彼らはたくさん使います
shellfish
貝類
We were five thousand years ago
私たちは5000年前にいました
South Guan Li Dong Healing Inside
South Guan Li Dong ヒーリング インサイド
have more than
以上のものを持っています
Seventy-seven different kinds of these shellfish
77種類の貝類
good
良い
how do we learn about these shellfish
これらの貝についてどうやって学ぶのですか
Director Wang is here
王監督はここにいます
i want to take this opportunity
この機会を利用したいです
Special thanks also to Director Wang
王監督にも感謝します
President Wang Teacher Wang
王学長 王先生
When I was doing my doctoral thesis
博士論文を書いていたとき
make shellfish
貝類を作る
In addition to identification
身分証明書に加えて
We do the analysis of probing isotopes
プローブ同位体の分析を行っています
Analysis of Probe Isotopes
プローブ同位体の分析
To understand the water environment
水環境を理解するために
Analysis of trophic isotopes
栄養同位体の分析
To understand the temperature of the water body
水域の温度を知るには
That is to say, from the temperature of the water body
つまり、水域の温度から
let's find out
確認してみましょう
when were these shellfish caught
これらの貝はいつ捕獲されましたか
when did you step on it
いつ踏んだの？
because shellfish when he was alive
生きていた頃は貝だったから
every day he grows
毎日彼は成長します
one of his growth
他的一個生長文
while growing
生長的同時
he will record
彼は記録します
A content of the aquatic environment of his life history
彼の生活史の水環境の内容
good
良い
from Nanguanli
南関里から
This is a statistical analysis of Yuzi in Nanguanli
これは南関里のYuziの統計分析です。
we found
私たちは見つけました
This so-called Ke Wenhai Scroll
このいわゆる柯文海巻物
Internet Scroll
インターネットスクロール
Can you find out
分かりますか
This is like what we are eating now
これは私たちが今食べているものと同じです
Chick Ray's body type
チック・レイの体型
I even want to tell you
私もあなたに言いたい
five thousand years
五千年
eat this chick ray
このひよこエイを食べてください
or the so-called sea rolls
またはいわゆるシーロール
method is the same
方法は同じです
just put that head
その頭を置いてください
remove and suck
取り外して吸う
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
Everyone should have experience with this hat.
誰もがこの帽子をかぶった経験があるはずです。
In particular, let me explain to you
特にご説明させていただきますと、
this is
これは
I want to talk to you
あなたとお話がしたいです
We all live in a test room
私たちは皆、テストルームに住んでいます
Apart from eating shellfish, these people
これらの人々は貝類を食べる以外にも、
They even used those shells as tools
彼らはその貝殻を道具としてさえ使用しました
This is an extinct window
これは消滅したウィンドウです
or Yunmuge
またはゆんむげ
Besides eating shells, they
彼らは貝殻を食べるだけでなく、
In addition to eating shellfish
貝類を食べる以外にも
Shells are also used as shell knives
貝殻は貝殻ナイフとしても使用されます
You can see these sentences
これらの文を見ることができます
we have asked
私たちは尋ねました
an archaeologist who specializes in this oceania
このオセアニアを専門とする考古学者
he came to tell us
彼は私たちに告げるために来た
This is likely to be in
これはおそらく入っています
It is a tool for removing the skin of sweet potatoes and sweet potatoes like this kind of follow-up
このようなフォローアップのようなサツマイモやサツマイモの皮を剥くための道具です
In addition to eating and using them, everyone also uses them as a water product for wooden sticks
食べたり使ったりするだけでなく、木の棒のお供の水としても皆さんにご利用いただいています。
We even think that its probable representative social status
私たちは、その社会的地位を代表する可能性が高いとさえ考えています。
They even have so-called symbols of faith
いわゆる信仰の象徴さえあります
Why? Most of the time we see only five thousand years ago.
なぜでしょうか? ほとんどの場合、私たちが目にするのは 5,000 年前だけです。
They put shells on top of their ears and noses
彼らは耳と鼻の上に貝殻を置きます
They made a lot of these shells as an ornament
彼らはこの貝殻を飾りとしてたくさん作りました
The analysis of carbon and oxygen isoples we performed
私たちが行った炭素と酸素の同位体の分析
Want to understand from 5000 years, 4000 years, 3000 years, 2000 years
5000年、4000年、3000年、2000年から知りたい
These shellfish extant in these ruins until late
この遺跡で遅くまで生き残っていた貝類
What kind of environment did you grow up in?
どのような環境で育ちましたか？
What time and season are these communities collecting
これらのコミュニティが収集している時間と季節は何ですか
Well, this is just a little introduction to you first.
さて、これは最初に少しだけご紹介します。
this is a letter
これは手紙です
We go from the top of the shell to this edge of the shell
シェルの上部からシェルのこの端まで進みます
Then every other this distance
それから、この距離ごとに
let's sample it
サンプリングしてみましょう
Take a sample of it and there's something called calcium carbonate in it
サンプルを採取してみると、炭酸カルシウムと呼ばれるものが含まれています。
give us a chance to extract its carbon and oxygen
炭素と酸素を抽出する機会を与えてください
to understand one of them
そのうちの一つを理解するために
A cultivation of the same quality
同じ品質の栽培
Okay, so this is what we started from Dabankeng
さて、これが大晩坑から始まったことです
Five thousand years ago to Niuzhou paper
5000年前の牛州紙へ
This is about four thousand years old
これは約4000年前のものです
Let's analyze a sample of it
そのサンプルを分析してみましょう
to understand in the aquatic environment
水環境で理解する
So most of the food is in Hehaikou
ほとんどの食べ物は河海口にあります
A remnant closer to a freshwater environment
淡水環境に近い残骸
This is from the Great Lakes Culture and the Bird Culture
これは五大湖の文化と鳥の文化から来ています
A comparison of what we see when
いつ見えるのかの比較
They are almost all in the same water environment.
それらはほぼすべて同じ水環境にいます。
Even Sheila's
シーラさんでも
So our observation like this
したがって、私たちの観察は次のとおりです
we are accompanied by the present
私たちは現在とともにあります
what we can collect
私たちが収集できるもの
These records of temperature and rainfall in the southwestern waters of Taiwan
台湾南西部海域の気温と降水量の記録
let's see it
それを見てみましょう
some of their variations
それらのバリエーションのいくつか
And then comparing these different seasons that we're seeing
そして、私たちが見ているこれらの異なる季節を比較してください
One oxygen composition of all these carbon-oxygen isotopes
これらすべての炭素 - 酸素同位体の 1 つの酸素組成
So in an analysis like this
したがって、このような分析では
we can find out
私たちは知ることができます
A distance from the Nanke ruins where it is now
現在の南柯遺跡からの距離
with the coastline
海岸線とともに
In fact, a change in the water environment is not big
実は水環境の変化はそれほど大きくない
is very similar
とても似ています
But we found
しかし、私たちは見つけました
Like, say, this is a telescope screw
たとえば、これは望遠鏡のネジです
This is mangrove insurance
これがマングローブ保険です
this is blood and sweat
これは血と汗だ
This is window north is extinct
これは窓北は絶滅しました
Is that man-made or a change in the environment?
それは人為的なものでしょうか、それとも環境の変化でしょうか？
One of the resources responsible for these multipliers
これらの乗数を担当するリソースの 1 つ
We started with these Taiwanese assistants who entered the latest
私たちは、最近入社した台湾人のアシスタントからスタートしました。
Inside a map from about four hundred years ago
約400年前の地図の中
can also be found
も見つかります
A change in the environment of these waters
この海域の環境の変化
with what we see now
私たちが今見ているものと一緒に
that way
そうやって
we can also understand
私たちにも理解できます
Inland it contributes to the whole environment
内陸では環境全体に貢献します
Sensitivity is likely
過敏症の可能性が高い
not easy enough to give them a chance
彼らにチャンスを与えるほど簡単ではない
to adapt and survive
適応して生き残るために
So especially those types of backs that I just saw
だから特に今見たようなタイプの背中は
The only difference is
唯一の違いは、
what you know now
あなたが今知っていること
What is the most famous snack in Taiwan called?
台湾で最も有名なスナックは何と呼ばれますか?
wow really
うわー本当に
It won't be a small bar
小さなバーではないでしょう
I spent two years following Ke Ming of Qigude
私は七德の柯明を追って2年間を過ごしました
There is a man named Conan
コナンという男がいる
This Conan belongs to Haiyan Institute of National Taiwan University
このコナンは国立台湾大学海塩研究所のものです
half read
読みかけ
Then I grabbed a few Konuli
それから私はいくつかのコヌリをつかみました
Go to his boss and say I quit
彼の上司のところに行って、辞めると言いなさい
I'm going home to plant Ke
ケを植えるために家に帰ります
yes
はい
But everybody
でもみんな
just said that
ちょうどそれを言いました
In fact, I want to tell you
実は、あなたに伝えたいのですが、
a change in the environment
環境の変化
What is caused is a change in environmental resources
何が原因で環境資源が変化するのか
One of the above patterns adapted to humans
上記のいずれかのパターンを人間に適応させたもの
an application of the strategy
戦略の応用
This is what we often think about
これは私たちがよく考えることです
good
良い
Four thousand years ago, these shells had spring, summer, autumn, and winter, and they were almost average, which reflected what it might be like. They had shells in spring, summer, autumn and winter, and they were not enough to eat because they were grown by themselves.
4000年前、これらの貝には春、夏、秋、冬があり、その貝殻はほぼ平均的で、それがどのようなものかを反映していました。春、夏、秋、冬に貝があり、食べるには十分ではありませんでした。自分たちで育ててきたものだから。
Four thousand years ago, there were many springs and winters, a little less autumn, and almost no summer.
4000年前には、春と冬が多く、秋は少し少なくなり、夏はほとんどありませんでした。
More than 3,000 years ago were also spring, summer, autumn, and winter, so these Han people who came in from 5,000, 4, and 3,000 years until the late arrival,
3000年以上前も春、夏、秋、冬だったので、5000年、4000年、3000年前から遅れてやって来た漢民族は、
Living in the same environment in the southwestern waters of Taiwan, how to use these shellfish resources, this is to provide us with a very clear understanding.
台湾の南西海域で同じ環境に住んでいると、これらの貝類資源がどのように利用されるのか、これは非常に明確な理解を与えてくれます。
Yes, in fact, in 2004, I was on the first floor of the southwestern waters of Taiwan,
はい、実際、2004 年に私は台湾の南西海域の 1 階にいました。
At the request of the former vice president Zhu Jinyi and Mr. Zhu
朱真儀・元副総統と朱氏の要請により
At that time, it seemed that Vice President Wang asked me to write it.
その時、王副総統から私に書いてほしいと頼まれたようです。
Taiwan's first rice and first dog
台湾初の米と初の犬
In fact, we also want to thank our teacher Xi
実際、私たちの先生、Xiにも感謝したいと思います。
Teacher Xi is the rice and millet that his team gave us the opportunity to really know
習氏は彼のチームが私たちに本当に知る機会を与えてくれた米と雑穀である
We even recently discovered that there was more than one kind of millet five thousand years ago
私たちは最近、5000年前には複数の種類のキビが存在していたことさえ発見しました。
Let Teacher Xi tell the story behind this
習先生にこの裏話を語ってもらいましょう
But the most important meaning is where
しかし、最も重要な意味はどこにあるのかということです
when we started school
私たちが学校を始めたとき
twenty years ago thirty years ago
二十年前 三十年前
To rice will spread to Taiwan
お米が台湾に広がる
At least after 3000 AD
少なくとも西暦3000年以降には
things that can happen
起こり得ること
Results of Nanke's Discovery
南科の発見の結果
Destroyed all previous acquaintances
これまでの知識をすべて破壊した
This is a very typical
これは非常に典型的なものです
very specific answer
非常に具体的な答え
from different times
さまざまな時代から
five thousand four thousand three thousand
五千四千三千
until the latest
最近まで
We start from the morphometric
形態計測から始めます
got to know them when
彼らと知り合ったとき
whatever you want
あなたが望むものなら、なんでも
one content on rice left over
残ったご飯に中身1つ
Take Nanguanli five thousand years ago
5000年前の南関里を例に挙げましょう
with four thousand years ago
四千年前と
let's do a comparison
比較してみましょう
Small grain rice Medium grain rice Large grain rice
小粒米 中粒米 大粒米
Compare it like this
こうやって比較してみます
we can find out
私たちは知ることができます
how about some of them
そのうちの何人かはどうですか
This means that our own technology allows them to have the development of the whole concept
これは、当社独自の技術によりコンセプト全体の開発が可能になることを意味します。
So we can also infer what kind of species they are planning.
したがって、彼らが計画している種の種類を推測することもできます。
These are all things that give us the opportunity to witness the content of agricultural cultivation in Taiwan over the past 5,000 years
これらはすべて、過去 5,000 年にわたる台湾の農業の内容を目の当たりにする機会を与えてくれます。
It is the legacy that I mentioned to you just now that there are 2,000 in Nanke and now there are nearly 2,500
南科には 2,000 人がいて、今では 2,500 人近くになっているのは、先ほどお話しした遺産です。
These remnants from 5,000 years ago you can see and see is an official form of health care straight limbs and their heads
5,000 年前のこれらの残骸は、医療の正式な形式であるまっすぐな手足とその頭を見ることができます。
They are all facing south, can you guys find them?
全部南を向いているんですが、見つけられるでしょうか？
such a consistency
そのような一貫性
Many times when we go to give speeches in different places
いろいろな場所に講演に行くときは何度も
someone will bring it up
誰かがそれを持ち出すだろう
So how do they buy it?
では、彼らはどうやってそれを買うのでしょうか？
Was there a paper back needle or a paper blue needle five thousand years ago?
5,000年前にペーパーバック針やペーパーブルー針は存在しましたか?
Do you have?
ありますか？
Can anyone tell me how they buy it?
誰かどうやって購入するのか教えてもらえますか？
look at the sky
空を見て
Come, come, you are already the one you know the most
さあ、さあ、あなたはもうあなたが一番よく知っている人です
Hurry up and give you something first
急いで何かを先にあげてください
this
これ
Classic magazine helped us out
クラシック雑誌が私たちを助けてくれました
Yes, look at the sky, when will it come?
そう、空を見てください、いつ来るのでしょう？
I look at it at night, do you buy it at night when you buy it?
夜に見ていますが、買うときは夜に買いますか？
Buy during the day and watch at night
日中に買って夜に見る
I'll sort this out when I get back.
戻ったらこれを整理します。
You are all my providers of this information
皆さんは私のこの情報の提供者です
At that time, my speech fee will also be taken out.
その際、私の講演料も引かれてしまいます。
Get it out
出してください
ok guys did you see this
はい、皆さん、これを見ましたか？
one-on-one
一対一
Is this a standard monogamous account?
これは標準的な一夫一婦制アカウントですか?
Teacher Li Li Aping
リー・リー・アピン先生
How many people are there now?
今何人いますか？
I didn't say it was you who said it
あなたが言ったとは言っていません
ok this is one
まあ、これは一つです
But in fact they are different
しかし実際にはそれらは違います
More than 80% have very high consistency
80% 以上が非常に高い一貫性を持っています
how do we explain these
これらをどう説明すればよいでしょうか
Surprise or what?
驚きか何か？
At this time, we sometimes think about whether they are the same group of people
このとき、私たちは彼らが同じグループなのかどうかを時々考えます。
If it's not when they're in the same group
同じグループにいるときでなければ
They treat the dead differently
彼らは死者に対する扱いが違う
We can even see the disturbing
不穏なものさえ見えます
if you are more specific
もっと具体的に言うなら
This one is in the ash pit not in the real male tree
これは本物の雄の木ではなく、灰穴の中にあります
The so-called one of their male wood-shaped system above
上記の男性の木型システムのいわゆる 1 つ
Well, Guanmu already existed five thousand years ago
さて、関武は5000年前にすでに存在していました
This is the viewing board pressed against this individual
これがこの人物に押し付けられた閲覧板です
So you can also know
それであなたも知ることができます
Using wooden coffins is not something we have now
木棺の使用は今ではありません
Four thousand years ago in Taiwan already had
4000年前、台湾ではすでに
four thousand years ago
四千年前
one of their males
彼らの男性の一人
Jinmu Xingzi is the whole strip
Jinmu Xingzi はストリップ全体です
also face male
顔も男性
Health straight limb
養生直肢
The difference is what they already have
違いは彼らがすでに持っているものです
Bow off
お辞儀をする
These bows are key to our understanding
これらの弓は私たちの理解の鍵です
two years or younger
2歳以下
a rational way of doing this
これを行うための合理的な方法
such a life theory
そんな人生論
one way of treating
治療の一つの方法
It's beyond our imagination
それは私たちの想像を超えています
Everyone, in fact, when we discovered
みんな、実は発見したときは
never thought what this is
これが何なのか考えたこともなかった
Because I haven't seen the bones yet
まだ骨見てないから
We even ran to Echime Hospital
八目病院にも走って行きました
Go borrow Potable's X-ray
Potable の X 線を借りに行く
I can't even take a photo
写真すら撮れない
As a result, we really
その結果、私たちは本当に、
it's clearing slowly
ゆっくりと晴れていく
Only found out after clearing
クリア後​​に初めて分かりました
There is indeed a staff
まさに羊飼いの杖ですね
well , 3000 years ago
まあ、3000年前
Guys, can you see it?
皆さん、見えますか？
Each cane is a handful
各杖は一握りです
three five six eight
三五六八
There are adults, there are children
大人もいるし子供もいる
This is for adults, this is for children
これは大人用、これは子供用です
But the way their heads are facing
でも彼らの頭の向きは
has changed
変更されました
towards the north
北に向かって
Even the way of one of their rods
スタッフの一人のやり方さえも
After shepherding
羊飼いの後
above the head, thirty to fifty centimeters
頭上30センチから50センチ
ranging from twenty to thirty centimeters
二十センチから三十センチまで
There's a funerary jar on it
その上に葬式の壺があります
This is also what we had in this era more than 3,000 years ago.
これは3000年以上前のこの時代にもあったものです。
trees that were able to receive these jars very intact
これらの瓶を非常に無傷で受け取ることができた木々
most evidence
ほとんどの証拠
Everyone can also understand that there are all kinds of different views
いろんな考え方があることは誰でもわかる
Not just in the thick
厚いだけではない
We even found that some are placed on the ground first
最初に地面に置かれるものもあることがわかりました
Then take the pot upside down and the upside down one
次に、鍋を逆さまにして、逆さまにしたものを取り出します
Well, we even found headless
まあ、首なしも見つけました
Some are not accompanied by shells like those five thousand years ago.
5000年前のような貝殻を伴わないものもある。
There is a back and a back is the kind of necklace with a back
裏があって裏があるタイプのネックレスです
They reflect men's online crimes
それらは男性のオンライン犯罪を反映しています
women follow interview
女性はインタビューに従う
Some are different from Yugou and so on.
ユーゴウなどと違うところもある。
By the Iron Age, the whole reason for life changed
鉄器時代までに、人生の理由全体が変わった
At this time, one of their barriers
このとき、彼らの障壁の一つは、
Knowledge remains the same, head to the north, straight
知識はそのまま 北へまっすぐ
But some of them found
しかし、そのうちの何人かは見つけました
What we found was that he took the pieces of the head first
我々が発見したのは、彼が最初に頭の破片を取り出したということだった
paved on the ground, and then the human individual
地面に舗装され、そして人間の個体
put it on top, there is indeed a
それを上に置いてください、確かにあります
Peach tube , but no longer what
ピーチチューブ、でももう何？
Thirty to fifty centimeters above the head, fifty or sixty centimeters high
頭上30～50センチ、高さ50～60センチ
this place, above this place
この場所、この場所の上
Yes, these are all for us to understand
はい、これらはすべて私たちが理解できることです
a change in these cultures
これらの文化の変化
Is it the difference between people? Or the difference in the whole era?
人の違いなのか、それとも時代の違いなのか。
And with
そして、
we also found
私たちも見つけました
this person
この人
His head was given in a clay basin
彼の頭は粘土の洗面器に入れられました
put it away
かたずけて
This will be explained to you later
これについては後ほど説明します
this is what we think
これが私たちの考えです
Another evidence of headhunting
ヘッドハンティングのもう一つの証拠
good
良い
As here we can find that
ここでそれがわかります
He uses
他用
into the limb bones to make this
これを手足の骨に埋め込む
Link Force Fishhook
リンクフォースフィッシュフック
accompanied by
を伴う
next to the individual
個人の隣に
in this era
この時代に
Besides this
このほかにも
They are even accompanied by
さらには
ironware
鉄器
the only difference
唯一の違い
bath gas replaced by glassware
お風呂のガスをガラス製品に置き換える
good
良い
what's next
次は何ですか
Let me introduce one more
もう一つ紹介させてください
Taiwan's logistics economy
台湾の物流経済
Taiwan's logistics economy is not
台湾の物流経済はそうではない
only now
今だけ
I often think
よく思うのですが
The transportation in Taiwan is inconvenient and inconvenient
台湾の交通は不便で不便です
let me experience it myself
自分自身で体験させてください
Just now the dean said that I am in Hengchun
今、学部長が私が恒春にいると言いました
Yes, when I started working in Hengchun in 1993
はい、1993年に私が恒春で働き始めたとき
at that time
その時
On the first day, I have to take the train to Kaohsiung to stay overnight.
初日は電車で高雄まで行き一泊しなければなりません。
At six o'clock the next morning, take the Guoguang ship to Hengchun
翌朝6時に国光船で恒春へ向かいます。
Inconvenient
不便
really inconvenient
本当に不便です
Sometimes I can't catch the Guoguang number
国光番号が聞き取れない場合があります
you want to take a wild bike
ワイルドバイクに乗りたいですか
you still worry
あなたはまだ心配しています
near marriage
結婚間近
yes
はい
But
しかし
you never thought
あなたは考えたこともありませんでした
Logistics in Taiwan started five thousand years ago
台湾の物流は5000年前に始まった
surprise you
あなたを驚かせます
scheming
陰謀
this is my favorite
これは私のお気に入りです
It's not this bullshit
こんなデタラメじゃないよ
you guys know what this is
皆さん、これが何なのか知っていますか
Taiwan domain
台湾ドメイン
Is it everywhere in Taiwan?
台湾のどこにでもあるんですか？
Where
どこ
Clam
蛤
who said the wind
誰が風を言ったのか
The one I can't post here
ここには載せられないもの
basically for you
基本的にあなたのために
come on and write
さあ、書いてください
Thanks
ありがとう
good
良い
How did the domain of Fengtian reach Tainan five thousand years ago
5000年前、奉天の領土はどのようにして台南に到達したのか
sorry i should have brought it to you
ごめんなさい、あなたに持ってくるべきでした
Thanks
ありがとう
how come thank you
どうしてですか、ありがとう
yes
はい
domain arrow
ドメイン矢印
domain collapse
ドメイン崩壊
The one on the far right lets call it
一番右にあるものを、
Although basalt
玄武岩ですが
certainly
そうです
Teacher Chen Wenshan is not here, he scolds us every time
陳文山先生はここにはいません、彼はいつも私たちを叱ります
Why do you choose Wuyan when you see an infection, and you think it’s from Penghu?
感染症を見て澎湖産だと思うのになぜ武岩を選ぶのですか？
How did Penghu come here five thousand years ago?
5000年前、澎湖はどのようにしてここに来たのでしょうか？
You're so loud, so brave, give you one
あなたはとてもうるさくて、とても勇敢なので、あなたに一つあげてください
Thank you, let you get to know Brother Nan better when I go home
ありがとう、家に帰ったらナン兄弟のことをもっと知りましょう
Well, how did these baths from 5,000 years ago come to Tainan?
では、5,000年前のこの浴場はどのようにして台南に伝わったのでしょうか？
It doesn't matter. Four thousand years ago, people were still doing bathing?
どうでもいいけど、4000年前も人はまだ入浴してたんですか？
They still have baths, but what?
まだお風呂はありますが、何でしょうか？
What about the bath rings? How about all of them?
バスリングはどうですか? 全部はどうですか?
How is it still clear?
どうしてまだはっきりしているのですか？
still above his elbow
まだ肘の上にある
yes
はい
3000 years ago
3000年前
Wow
おお
This string, this string, we want this and that
この文字列、この文字列、あれもこれも欲しい
see how much
いくらか見てください
yes
はい
5000 years 4000 years 3000 years
5000年 4000年 3000年
This group of people live on the southwest coast of Taiwan
このグループは台湾の南西海岸に住んでいます
how did they come
彼らはどうやって来たのですか
How come there are these so-called
どうしてこれらのいわゆるものがあるのですか
Toyota from Hualien
花蓮のトヨタ
come these baths
このお風呂に来てください
pretty
かわいい
These really make us
これらは本当に私たちを作ります
very surprised
とても驚いた
Are they a group of people?
彼らは人々のグループですか？
specialized in these trades
これらの取引に特化した
There is another group of people who specialize in
これを専門とする別のグループがあります
The people who made these crafts
これらの工芸品を作った人々
Or do they know how to find these people themselves?
それとも、彼らは自分でこれらの人々を見つける方法を知っていますか？
for exchange
交換用
Of course they are so-called noble artifacts
もちろんいわゆる名器ですよ
Absolutely we can believe
絶対に私たちは信じられる
I just showed you this
これを見せたばかりです
This is also found in the ruins of "Shanbaopi"
こちらも「山宝堡」の遺跡で発見されています。
like this individual above
上のこの人のように
Two or three hundred of these pre-tube beads
このプレパイプビーズが200～300個
Speaking of which
そういえば
I also want to introduce to you
こちらも紹介したいと思います
Just now the dean also mentioned
先ほど学部長もおっしゃいました
Mr Zhang also mentioned
張氏も言及した
Taiwan as an Austronesian Aboriginal
オーストロネシア先住民としての台湾
a base on which the nation resides
国家が居住する基地
Mr. Zhang Guangzhi
張光直先生
in 1987
1987年に
He wrote very clearly
彼は非常に明確に書いた
In an article like this
こんな記事で
described
説明された
On the traceability of the South Island
南島のトレーサビリティについて
From the perspective of the garden-like relationship of culture
庭園的な文化関係の視点から
what can we discover
私たちは何を発見できるでしょうか
rental dog for hunting
狩猟用のレンタル犬
Make naughty, make columns, etc.
エッチなことをしたり、コラムを作ったり。
come down like this
こうやって降りてくる
with seafaring technology and with barkcloth
航海技術と樹皮布を使用した
Wait, there are rice and millet ones
待て、米と雑穀があるよ
is from the above
上からです
everybody
みんな
vaguely should be able to understand
漠然とは理解できるはず
Taiwan as a
としての台湾
A Yuan Township of Minamishimabara Democracy
南島原民主主義の元郷
doesn't seem too much
あまり多くないようです
1910 1910
1910年 1910年的
In a record of Ugly Nosuke
醜いノスケの記録に
he can see
彼は見える
This is definitely not Wu Feng's story
これは決してウー・フェンの物語ではありません
Well, the scene that the Dutch saw when they came to Tainan,
さて、オランダ人が台南に来たときに見た光景、
This is what our ornithine culture saw 2000 years ago. A headhunter,
これは私たちのオルニチン文化が 2000 年前に見たものです。
These wooden sticks without heads seen 3000 years ago,
3000年前に見られた頭のない木の棒、
and the three fist teeth we saw 5,000 years ago,
そして5000年前に見た拳の3本の歯、
They also pierced a hole,
彼らはまた穴を開けました、
Teacher Zhang Guangren also thinks that this is all left over from evidence from a headhunter.
張光仁教師も、これはすべてヘッドハンターの証拠から残ったものだと考えています。
So 5000 years all the way down,
つまり、5000年もずっと下まで、
There seems to be a thread,
スレもあるみたいですが、
Let us tell us about the inner relationship between these ancestors,
これらの先祖たちの内なる関係についてお話ししましょう。
Yes or no?
はい、もしくは、いいえ？
and another,
そしてもう一つ、
a custom of tooth extraction
抜歯の習慣
In the material of our national system
私たちの国家システムの資料の中で
We can still see and chase
私たちはまだ見て追いかけることができます
Explained again and again
何度も何度も説明した
Did they follow these peoples
彼らはこれらの人々に従ったのでしょうか
a close relationship
密接な関係
Bark Cloth Sticks These Faux Wheels
樹皮布がこれらのフェイクホイールに貼り付けられます
braiding
編み込み
the tools they use
彼らが使用するツール
Finally I told you
最後に言いました
When did the Han people start coming in?
漢民族はいつから流入し始めましたか?
The culture of the Han people began to come in in large numbers
漢民族の文化が大量に流入し始めた
Definitely not a post-1949 thing
決して1949年以降のものではない
What we saw in Tainan
台南で見たもの
I used to talk to Tainan's new style
台南の新しいスタイルについてよく話しました
used to be the mayor
かつて市長だった
I said that the new style used to be outside Taiwan
新しいスタイルはかつては台湾の外にあったと私は言いました
The first place to meet international standards
国際基準を満たす最初の場所
He said I was kissing his ass
彼は私が彼のお尻にキスをしていると言った
Teacher Zhu is here
朱先生が来ました
Miss Zhu, can you
朱さん、お願いできますか？
Teacher Zhu is a caring person
朱先生は思いやりのある人です
The Heart Has the Earliest Church
心には最も古い教会がある
Definitely not Wanhua
絶対万華じゃないよ
Definitely not Wanjin
絶対にワンジンじゃないよ
Definitely not freshwater
絶対淡水じゃないよ
ass church
お尻の教会
It's something on your mind, right?
それは気になることですよね？
But I still want to tell you
でも、それでも伝えたい
you wait and see
あなたは待って見てください
an entry into these material cultures
これらの物質文化への入り口
Indeed a large number of these come in
確かにこういうのが大量に入ってきますね
In our Han settlements
私たちの漢民族の居住地では
where we meet the aborigines
先住民と出会う場所
Industry in the Tang Department
唐当館産業部
Yes, earlier than Henan people have entered the southwestern coast of Taiwan, especially the wells in Tainan area,
はい、河南よりも早く、人々は台湾の南西海岸、特に台南地域の井戸に入りました。
That is to say, water wells are not only used by Han people, we have so-called soil wells four thousand years ago,
つまり、水井戸は漢民族だけが使っているわけではなく、4000年前にもいわゆる土井戸があったのです。
But knowing how to make it like this is definitely a technique that Han people have.
しかし、このように作る方法を知っていることは間違いなく漢民族が持っている技術です。
Bullock carts, Taiwan does not have cattle, Taiwan has cattle brought in from outside, as if I want to tell you, the number one dog in Taiwan that I did not talk about today,
牛車、台湾には牛がいない、台湾には外から持ち込まれた牛がいる、今日は話さなかった台湾ナンバーワンの犬を教えてあげたいかのように、
There are no dogs in Taiwan. Dogs in Taiwan are brought in by people.
台湾には犬がいません、台湾の犬は人間によって持ち込まれます。
This concept, everyone should know that only Han people have it.
この概念は漢民族だけが持っていることを誰もが知っておくべきです。
curtain
カーテン
Ladies and gentlemen, we have seen the curtain five thousand years ago
皆さん、私たちは五千年前の幕を見ました。
The curtain of four thousand years ago, until now
四千年前の幕、今まで
iron age right? yes
鉄器時代ですよね？はい
Is there such a pattern?
そういうパターンもあるんでしょうか？
No, this is what Han people have
いいえ、これが漢民族の持つものです
When will it happen? Han people will come in in large numbers
いつ起こりますか? 漢民族が大量にやってくるでしょう
After bringing in one of his etiquette rules,
彼のエチケットルールの一つを導入した後、
they will have such a
彼らはそのようなものを持つでしょう
This is solid evidence
これは確かな証拠です
Do you believe in Buddhism?
あなたは仏教を信じますか？
Whole Buddha Mother
仏陀の母全体
inside our screen
私たちの画面の中
For this copper coin, he took his original
この銅貨のために、彼はオリジナルを取り出しました。
The lines on the pillars on the surface were worn away
表面の柱のラインが削れてしまいました
Ko's
コウさん
Yes, this also explains
はい、これでも説明できます
Taiwan
台湾
When will the mother of the whole Buddha, this branch, come?
仏陀全体の母、この枝はいつ来ますか？
Originally, they all thought that when Zheng Chenggong came in, what year was it?
もともと、鄭成功が入ってきたとき、それは何年だったのか、と皆が思っていました。
There is no high school, everyone is in the fourth grade and fifth grade, forget it
高校なんてない、みんな4年生と5年生、忘れてください
This, this, this, no, Mr. Xing, I will give you a copy later
これ、これ、これ、いいえ、シンさん、後でコピーを渡します
Yes, Hengran came in 1624
はい、ヘンランは 1624 年に来ました
Zheng Chenggong came in 1662,38 years
鄭成功は 1662 年 38 年に来日しました。
However, such a time is different from what we now know about Qingkang in 1684.
しかし、そのような時代は、私たちが現在知っている1684年の青康時代とは異なります。
caused by that time, even earlier
その時、さらに以前のことによって引き起こされた
This is all explained, how about it, the Han people came in
これですべて説明がつきましたが、どうですか、漢民族が入ってきたのです。
I was dumbfounded when I saw this one, once I was a child
子供の頃にこれを見たときは唖然としました
I'll talk about what's on my mind
思っていることを話します
they see this
彼らはこれを見ます
they say no
彼らはノーと言います
Little ones love to scrape off
小さなお子様は削り取るのが大好きです
My Taiwanese is not correct
私の台湾語は正しくありません
everyone is still laughing
みんなまだ笑ってる
The company came out because of the chairs in the company
会社がなくなったのは会社の椅子のせいだ
The thing about the chair coming out of the company
会社から出てくる椅子のこと
This is ironclad evidence
これは鉄壁の証拠だ
deer feet do it
鹿の足がやります
Deer's foot to carve out
彫る鹿の足
four different
4つの異なる
Now scraping off is four, right?
これで削るのは4つですよね？
yes
はい
China's earliest eighth to twelfth centuries
中国最古の8世紀から12世紀
Dice of the eighth century
8世紀のサイコロ
good
良い
Speaking of this
これについて言えば
archeology
考古
actually tell you
実際に言ってください
Our ins and outs beyond ink
インクを超えた私たちの裏表
I often say
私はよく言います
Archeology
考古学
nothing good actually
実際には何も良いことはありません
But archeology is the experience of life
しかし、考古学は人生の経験です
I experience different chairs inside
室内でさまざまな椅子を体験
the story of my life told
私の人生の物語が語られました
i got inside the archaeological chair
私は考古学の椅子の中に入った
I go to learn other people's culture
他の人の文化を学びに行きます
no good or bad
良くも悪くもない
no high or low
高いも低いもない
you can say
あなたは言うことができます
This group of people fit in well or not
このグループの人々はうまく溶け込めるかどうか
Because every chair is like
どの椅子も似ているから
a group of people live there
人々のグループがそこに住んでいます
live after a certain time
一定時間後に生き続ける
they left
彼らは行ってしまった
Whether the reason for leaving is good or bad
退職理由が良いか悪いか
either positive or negative
ポジティブかネガティブかのどちらか
This is what we need from
これが私たちが必要としているものです
A pile of archaeological chairs inside
内部には考古学の椅子が山積み
come tell us
来て教えてください
But what I want to say about life and choices
でも人生と選択について言いたいことは
Time is changing this year, the environment is changing
今年は時代が変わり、環境も変わります
Many times borrowed from Tolstoy's
トルストイの本から何度も借りた
Still borrowing from Tolstoy
今もトルストイから借りている
Once you leave the path you are used to
慣れ親しんだ道を離れると
we'll think we're lost
私たちは道に迷ったと思うでしょう
But what?
でも何？
we are under our feet
私たちは足元にいます
A brand-new Kangzhuang Avenue is just about to open
真新しい康荘街がまもなくオープンします
i hope after tonight
今夜以降だといいけど
you will think differently
あなたは違う考え方をするでしょう
because we told you to
私たちがそうするように言ったから
Taiwan's 5,000 Years
台湾5000年
before this
この前に
Sponsor Wales
スポンサー ウェールズ
he is a biologist
彼は生物学者です
He made a vain complement to the genes of the whole world
彼は全世界の遺伝子を無駄に補完した
what is his purpose
彼の目的は何ですか
he said
彼は言った
we must know our own interests
私たちは自分自身の利益を知らなければなりません
to fully realize who you are
自分が誰であるかを完全に理解するために
Only then can we grasp the choice of where to go in the future
そうして初めて、私たちは将来どこに行くかの選択を把握することができます
This is a little bit of what I have studied archeology over the years
これは私が長年にわたって考古学を研究してきたことのほんの一部です
Accumulate all one perception
ひとつの認識をすべて積み重ねる
available to you
あなたが利用できる
because
なぜなら
Actually Taiwan is our home, right?
実は台湾は私たちの故郷ですよね？
As a Taiwanese, one cannot understand Taiwanese culture
台湾人として台湾文化を理解することはできない
Even with great wealth, the heart is empty
どんなに富があっても心は空っぽ
Nanke Medical Subgroup, Archaeological Research on Archaeological Medical Subgroup
南科医学分科会、考古学調査研究分科会
It is to provide us with an understanding of Taiwan's five thousand years of culture
台湾五千年の文化を理解するためのものです。
a platform for history
歴史のプラットフォーム
Why?
なぜ？
The foreground is in the National History Outline
前景は国史概要にあります
Give us another way of thinking
別の考え方を教えてください
Foreign nationals should have a little knowledge of their own history
外国人は自国の歴史について少しは知っておくべきだ
You Bi's Warmth and Tranquility to History
歴史に対するユビの温かさと静けさ
No extreme nihilism
極端なニヒリズムはありません
When believing that foreign nationals can meet the above-mentioned conditions
外国人であっても前各号に該当すると認められる場合
Taiwan has a future
台湾には未来がある
This is a little thought I want to offer you
これは私があなたに提供したい小さな考えです
thank you
ありがとう
very well said
非常によく言いました
Talking about a thousand years is like talking about small things
千年について語るのは小さなことについて話すようなもの
one afternoon before a family thing
家族の用事の前のある日の午後
Third sister
三番目の妹
I want to do a little more questions
もう少し質問したいです
Ask their two keynote speakers and filmmakers
2人の基調講演者と映画制作者に聞く
is it starting now
今から始まりますか
come on now start here
さあ、ここから始めましょう
ask Dr. Lee
リー博士に聞いてください
When did the name Taiwan start to be taken? Who took the name Taiwan?
台湾という名前はいつから使われ始めたのでしょうか? 台湾という名前は誰がつけたのでしょうか?
I'll give it to you first, don't ask me
先にあげますよ、聞かないでください
Dry warm, really
乾いて暖かい、本当に
When was Taiwan called Taiwan?
台湾が台湾と呼ばれるようになったのはいつですか?
Taiwan this
台湾これ
Taiwan from a Historical Perspective
歴史的観点から見た台湾
Or do you want to look at the name Taiwan
それとも台湾という名前を見たいですか？
The name Taiwan is actually
実は台湾という名前は、
very late
非常に遅く
Taiwan does not know me
台湾は私のことを知らない
Not the whole island, where is Taiwan
島全体ではありません、台湾はどこにありますか
Tainan, yes
台南、そうだね
when was taiwan borrowed
台湾はいつ借用されましたか
to cover the whole of Taiwan
台湾全土をカバーする
This is what we all have to think about
これは私たち全員が考えなければならないことです
This is one for all of us to think about
これは私たち全員が考えるべき問題です
Taiwan is not called Taiwan
台湾は台湾とは呼ばない
Dayuan
大園
Also called burying the injustice
不正を葬るとも言う
Taiwan
台湾
What are you talking about?
あなたは何について話していますか？
Taiwan is guilty
台湾は有罪だ
yes i just tell you this
はい、これだけは言っておきます
The rest you go to Google
残りは Google にアクセスしてください
yes
はい
Now that we are doing it, everyone wants to study Taiwan
こうなったらみんな台湾を勉強したいですよね
Experts from this research bureau in Taiwan
台湾のこの調査局の専門家
I saw the news in the newspaper not long ago
少し前に新聞でそのニュースを見ました
I want you to give me an answer
答えてほしい
That is to say, at that time, there were reports in the newspaper that in Indonesia
つまり、当時、インドネシアでは次のような報道が新聞にありました。
found one very well there
そこでとてもよくできたものを見つけました
row there
そこで漕ぐ
That is to say, about one meter
つまり1メートルくらい
that dampens the hobbit
それはホビットの気持ちを弱める
then i was thinking
それから私は考えていました
That is to say, our Lin Zhuyin has a machine called platooning machine.
つまり、うちのリン・ズインには隊列走行機という機体があるんです。
That is, Lin Zhuyin has a series called platooning machine
つまり、Lin Zhuyinには隊列走行マシンというシリーズがあります
That means he is a platoon machine
つまり彼は小隊マシンだ
Maybe it means he tracked down the assembly
おそらくそれは彼が集会を追跡したことを意味する
and is a
そして、
or at least touched
または少なくとも触れられた
Such a rowdy person
こういう人
I don't know if it's the element
それが元素なのかは分かりませんが
with this
これとともに
You say indonesia they hobbies won what's the relationship
あなたはインドネシアの趣味が勝つと言っていますが、その関係は何ですか？
very good
とても良い
Hahaha
ははは
Because I brought several copies today
今日は何冊か持ってきたので
Can't go home yet
まだ家に帰れない
So I'll give you that first
だから最初にそれをあげます
The Poet of the Fowles
ファウルズの詩人
not that
しないこと
The real Hobbies because he was made into a movie
映画化されたから本当の趣味
That's why I call him Hobbies
だから私は彼を「趣味」と呼んでいます
OK
OK
good
良い
It was actually different in those days
実はあの頃は違いました
The Hobbies should now be the Fowl poet
趣味は今、鳥の詩人になるべきです
The Dating I have now
私が今持っているデート
The current date seems to be more than 40,000 years.
現在の日付は4万年以上前であると思われます。
Zhang Xian
張賢
even earlier
もっと早くに
So this is what we call these
これを私たちはこう呼んでいます
The so-called short blacks are all together
いわゆる背の低い黒人が揃っています
talk
談
I
私
I will tell you an experience
体験談をお話します
once
一度
that is
あれは
Because at that time it seemed that
その時はそう見えたので、
That female Vice President Li Xiulian?
あの女性副大統領李秀蓮？
So when I'm sure
それで確信が持てたら
That's exactly what he posted
まさにそれが彼が投稿したものです
sea ​​black person's question
海の黒人の質問
The one at the pit management in Hengchun
恒春の坑道管理者
Liao's Liao's
リャオさん リャオさん
Are there any sea blacks here?
ここに海の黒人はいますか？
speak faster faster
より速く、より早く話す
That's hard to do
それは難しいです
Change to the opportunity to go online
オンラインに移行するチャンスに変える
This is called reporting
これをレポートといいます
can you make a name
名前を付けてもらえますか
this is one
これは 1 つです
I can't find any evidence so far
今のところ証拠が見つからない
we say this
私たちはこう言います
you want to talk about sea black
シーブラックについて話したいのですか
only one meter
たった1メートル
at least we have to say
少なくとも私たちは言わなければなりません
is he a child
彼は子供ですか
Are you still an adult?
あなたはまだ大人ですか？
right
右
But this figure actually has his range
しかし、この数字には実際に彼の範囲があります
But the real so-called dwarfs
しかし、本当のいわゆる小人たちは、
So far there is no such substantive evidence in Taiwan
今のところ台湾ではそのような実質的な証拠はない
Then you say this dwarf skill
それからあなたはこのドワーフのスキルを言います
Does it have anything to do with these dwarfs?
それはこれらの小人たちと何か関係がありますか？
We said that there are short blacks in the Philippines
フィリピンには小人の黒人がいると言われています
Wait a minute, maybe Mr. Zhang
ちょっと待ってください、張さんかもしれません
Mr. Zhang did this archaeology in the Philippines
張氏はフィリピンでこの考古学を行った
they have actual evidence of this
彼らはこれに関する実際の証拠を持っています
So far, there is no such evidence in Taiwan
今のところ台湾ではそのような証拠はない
OK
OK
I think this question is actually pretty good.
この質問は実に良い質問だと思います。
Because dwarfs actually have dwarf skills
ドワーフは実際にドワーフのスキルを持っているため、
I think that Academician Li just now
私は今、李学者がそう思ったと思います。
Where is Academician Li Renguo?
李仁国学者はどこにいますか？
He has written articles
彼は記事を書いています
Talking about the short black people in Taiwan
台湾の背の低い黒人について語る
But mainly from the legend
しかし主に伝説から
There are many tribes with legends about dwarfs
小人に関する伝説を持つ部族はたくさんあります
Are there any dwarfs?
小人はいますか？
In fact, in the past
実は過去に
Someone recently told me
最近ある人が私に言いました
I don't know if it's true or not
本当かどうかは分かりません
He said I'll tell you a secret
彼はあなたに秘密を教えてあげると言った
He said there is a place to keep secret now
彼は今秘密にしておくべき場所があると言った
Also punish the short black man like this
背の低い黒人もこのように罰してください
I said where is it?
ここはどこですか？と言いました。
He won't talk
彼は話さない
don't speak
話さないでください
But I can tell you
でも言えるよ
Now there are some clues
今、いくつかの手がかりがあります
clue
ヒント
What about the little black man?
小さな黒人男性はどうですか？
In fact, in Southeast Asia
実は東南アジアでは
is the branch of Malaysia
マレーシアの支店です
the Philippines
フィリピン
The three should be universal
この3つは普遍的であるべきです
that this
これは
Do you have this in Taiwan?
台湾にもこんなのあるんですか？
Then recently we were
それから最近、私たちは
Eight Immortals Cave
八仙洞
It is the ruins of the Eight Immortals Cave in Taitung
台東の八仙洞の遺跡です。
layer we found
私たちが見つけたレイヤー
About 5,000 to 6,000 years ago
約5000～6000年前
this level of culture
このレベルの文化
So the Nagahama culture that Han just talked about
それで、ハンさんが今話した長浜の文化。
The one tens of thousands of years earlier
数万年前のこと
there is one in the middle
中間有一個
There is an interval in the middle of more than 10,000 years
1万年以上の間隔がある
what about these things
これらのことはどうですか
it is also
それも
very simple times
とてもシンプルな時代
so very this this
とてもこれこれ
nor any naughtiness
いたずらもありません
Nor is there any such sign of agriculture
また、そのような農業の兆候はありません
but we think
しかし私たちは考えます
it does have
それはあります
people on this level exist
このレベルの人は存在する
Is it possible that this layer of people is a short black man?
この層が背の低い黒人男性である可能性はあるでしょうか？
So far we haven't found any human bones
今のところ人骨は見つかっていない
But from his cultural layer exists
しかし、彼の文化層からは
The world of five or six thousand years looks like
五千年か六千年後の世界はこんな感じ
and his periods are very similar to those of the Filipinos
彼の生理周期はフィリピン人の生理周期と非常に似ています
So we can only speculate
したがって、推測することしかできません
he may be a dwarf
彼は小人かもしれない
what about this part
この部分はどうですか
We hope that in the future there will be more and more evidence
今後、さらに多くの証拠が見つかることを期待しています
In fact, archeology is to slowly test
実際、考古学はゆっくりと検証することです
Accumulation of data bit by bit
データを少しずつ蓄積
Well, now there are some clues
さて、いくつかの手がかりが得られました
I believe that in the future this matter may
将来的にはこの問題が起こる可能性があると思います
There must be a way to make it clear one day
いつかそれを明らかにする方法があるはずです
i think this is there
これはあると思います
So as for the Flourish just now
さて、先ほどのFlourishですが、
It's this Hobby stuff
これはホビー関連のものです
Well, there are many different theories in this past
まあ、過去にはさまざまな理論があります
Some people think this may be modern man
これが現代人かもしれないと考える人もいる
he's just sick
彼はただ病気です
so he is short
だから彼は背が低い
about one meter high
大概一米高
Then the capacity is about 350 cm
そうすると容量は約350cmになります
Just 350CC
ちょうど350CC
Now our people are 1300CC
現在、当社の従業員は 1300CC です
Of course people now
もちろん今の人も
Then they only have 350CC
そうすると350CCしかない
Why are there such small people?
なんでこんなに小さい人がいるの？
So many people thought it was a kind of modern man
とても多くの人がそれを現代人のようなものだと思っていた
because he is very late
彼はとても遅刻するので
just ten thousand years
ちょうど一万年
is sick
病気です
But recent new research
しかし、最近の新しい研究では、
Already pushed back the age
もう時代は遡ってしまった
think he is not modern
彼は現代人ではないと思う
he may be an older
彼は年上かもしれない
Homo erectus
ホモ・エレクトス
only in Southeast Asia
東南アジアだけで
gradually affected by the environment
徐々に環境の影響を受ける
after isolation
隔離後
Will stay on this Flourish island
このフローリッシュ島に滞在します
So the problem is not solved yet
つまり問題はまだ解決されていない
There are still a lot of political discussions
政治的な議論はまだたくさんある
But it's always getting brighter
でもいつも明るくなってる
Now more and more evidence
今では証拠がどんどん増えている
Including a mathematical genetic evidence
数学的な遺伝的証拠を含む
Evidence that includes these cultural medicines
これらの文化的医薬品を含む証拠
Wait so we can learn more about it
詳細についてはお知らせしますのでお待ちください
So this so-called Flourish Men
つまり、このいわゆるFlourish Menは
what is going on
何が起こっている
welcome
いらっしゃいませ
Thanks
ありがとう
Come
来て
we are grateful
私たちは感謝しています
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
I am very grateful to Huang Mu Yuanchang this time
この度は黄武元昌さんに大変感謝しております
give me a chance to welcome
歓迎する機会を与えてください
I am a researcher at the Central Domestic Research Institute
私は中央国内研究所の研究員です。
Hong Deqian
ホン・ドチアン
First of all, I would also like to thank Zhang Yanshi and Teacher Li
まず第一に、張燕石先生と李先生にも感謝したいと思います。
so wonderful
とても素晴らしい
It's also very humorous, so the whole process will be very lively
とてもユーモアもあるので、作業全体がとても盛り上がります。
I personally also thank a lot
私個人としても大変感謝しております
Then I raised my hand mainly to see if I could get Mr. Liao
それから私は主に廖氏を獲得できるかどうかを確認するために手を挙げました。
go home
家に帰れ
a little scared
少し怖い
Then I just tell a little story
それからちょっとだけ話をします
I went to Willingdon, New Zealand in 1999 to attend a conference
1999年、私は会議に出席するためにニュージーランドのウィリンドンに行きました。
Then from the airport to the hotel where you leave
そして空港から出発するホテルまで
just hitchhike
ただヒッチハイクするだけ
Then cut the car driver to look like the name of the show
次に、車の運転手を番組名のようにカットします。
He also looked at me
彼も私を見た
then suddenly asked me
それから突然私に尋ねました
It seems that our competition is spiritually a little painful
私たちの競争は精神的に少し苦しいようです
He asked me if you are from Taiwan
彼はあなたが台湾出身かどうか私に尋ねました
I said yes
もちろん
He said that our ancestors
彼は言い​​ました、私たちの先祖は
seems to have a common ancestor
共通の祖先がいるらしい
He said they have a heart
彼らには心があると彼は言った
Since, as in 1999,
1999 年以来、
that is to say at that time
つまりその時は
Formal recognition of Māori ancestry may have come from Taiwan
マオリの祖先の正式な認識は台湾から来た可能性がある
So I just answer him
だから私はただ彼に答えるだけです
say we are brothers
私たちは兄弟だと言う
So let me feel at ease even when I'm bullying others
だから他人をいじめていても安心させてください
because abroad
海外だから
First time to New Zealand
初めてのニュージーランド
then i was curious
それから私は興味がありました
So three or four thousand years ago
つまり3千年か4千年前
How can there be a way to cross the ocean from Taiwan
台湾から海を渡る方法はあるのでしょうか？
as far as new zealand
ニュージーランドまで
Then wait until I visit their Rijksmuseum
それからアムステルダム国立美術館を訪れるまで待ってください
large-scale visitor
採訪的大物
because he has two canoes
彼はカヌーを２隻持っているので
That canoe has planks in the middle
そのカヌーには真ん中に板がある
And there are bamboo poles at the front and back to tie it up
前後に竹の棒があり、それを縛り付けます
So in the middle it can be
したがって、真ん中ではそれが可能です
Can be horizontal
水平にすることもできます
That is to say, traffic is also possible
つまり渋滞も可能です
because of this
このため
Only in this way is there a way to save the coolness
涼しさを保つ方法はこの方法だけです
So I feel very cooperative
だからとても協力的だと感じます
also very active
とても活発でもあります
Taiwan's coastal people crossed the sea beautifully so early
台湾沿岸の人々はこんなにも早く海を美しく渡った
Then in Australia there is a kind of tango
オーストラリアには一種のタンゴがあります
I heard that it is also native to Taiwan.
台湾のローカルフルーツでもあるそうです。
their present archaeological DNA finds
彼らの現在の考古学的DNAが発見したもの
It may have passed through Australia and then chased to Newia
オーストラリアを通過してからニューアまで追いかけてきた可能性がある
So many people in Newia like to translate
Newia には翻訳が好きな人がたくさんいます
This is very similar to the Yan Zhuwen in Taiwan
これは台湾の厳珠文によく似ています。
so i have a suggestion
そこで提案があります
That is to say, Newcia itself is kinder
つまりニューシア自体が優しいということだ。
He has a good reservation about Maori culture and chairs
彼はマオリの文化と椅子についてよく知っています
So our Zhuang Yan also has forty-one poems
それで、私たちの荘厳にも41の詩があります
should put this like this blue co chair
これをこの青い共同椅子のように置くべきです
Because this Lan Ke chair is more than ten years old
このLan Keチェアは10年以上前のものなので、
Is a national security officer of Taiwan
台湾の国家安全保障担当官です
Good things should be shared with this country
良いものはこの国と共有すべきだ
Therefore, cooperation should be strengthened
したがって、協力を強化する必要がある
Matsu
松
Taiwan Matsu should be present
台湾松もいるはず
Thank you for the above
以上 以上兼理 謝謝
Thanks
ありがとう
thanks for your question
ご質問ありがとうございます
but i tell you
でも私はあなたに言います
i have the same experience
私も同じ経験があります
I am here
私はここにいます
I forgot what year it is now
今何年か忘れた
There is a man named Force Leach
フォース・リーチという男がいる
He specializes in fish
彼は魚が専門です
he told me
彼は私に言った
He said the profiteers were probably from your Amis
彼は、暴利を貪ったのはおそらくあなたのアミ族の人々だと言いました
good
良い
I don't care
私は気にしない
I said I don't know
分からないと言いました
but he came to me
しかし彼は私のところに来ました
He especially ran to Taiwan
彼は特に台湾に来ました
because he went to hawaii
彼はハワイに行ったので
I heard I have a lot of fish in my hand
手にはたくさんの魚を持っていると聞きました
what fish
何の魚
variety of these fish
これらの魚のさまざまな
Especially the ghost knife
特にゴーストナイフ
Because he thought there was a group of people chasing ghost swords
妖刀を追っている集団がいると思ったから
from Taiwan all the way to New Zealand
台湾からはるばるニュージーランドまで
You believe it or you don't believe it
信じるか信じないか
Believers, Hengxin, but I want to tell you
信者の皆さん、ヘンシン、しかし私はあなたに言いたいのです
Peter Biaogu he thinks so too
ピーター・ビアオグ 彼もそう思う
He said that this group of people went out five thousand years ago
彼は、この人々のグループは5000年前に出て行ったと言いました
chasing ghost knife
ゴーストナイフを追って
I said you also want to eat fish, are you eating fish?
魚も食べたいって言ったけど、魚食べてるの？
where did ghost head knife come from
ゴーストヘッドナイフはどこから来たのか
Do you know this biological chain?
この生体連鎖をご存知ですか？
Do you know this flying fish medicine?
このトビウオの薬をご存知ですか？
When does flying fish medicine start
トビウオの薬はいつから始まりますか
The ghost knife came after the flying fish
トビウオを追ってゴーストナイフがやって来た
so i am
そう私は
And Lambi what will I see?
そしてランビは何を見るでしょうか？
The ghost head knife that started with the useless fish is here
ダメ魚から始まったゴーストヘッドナイフが登場
Ghost head knife is here
ゴーストヘッドナイフが登場
what came from
何が来たのか
fish name
魚の名前
what fish name
魚の名前は何ですか
please give me this room
この部屋をください
I'll give you one
一つあげます
your jokes are funny
あなたのジョークは面白いです
let everyone have a copy
みんなにコピーを持たせてください
After the ghost head knife comes, it will be a fin fish
ゴーストヘッドナイフが来たらヒレフィッシュになります
fin fish
ひれの魚
Hengchun's most famous
恒春で最も有名な
Broken Fish Umbrella
壊れた魚の傘
This is a biological store
ここは生物の店です
good
良い
But what is this?
しかし、これは何でしょうか？
go from south to north
南から北へ行く
Who is coming to the south?
誰が南に来るの？
everytime i talk to japanese
日本人と話すたびに
my very good
私のとても良い
he passed away last year
彼は昨年亡くなりました
everytime i go to japan
日本に行くたびに
i will
私はこれから
what would i bring mullet roe for him
彼にカラスミ何を持って行こうか
mullet roe
カラスミ
Mullet roe, everyone knows mullet roe
カラスミ、誰もが知っているカラスミ
Mullet roe, especially men like to eat it
カラスミ、特に男性が好んで食べます
But it's better not to eat
でも食べないほうがいいよ
Vice President Wang, you must not eat
王副総統、食べてはいけません
good
良い
when will the mullet come
ボラはいつ来ますか
everyone is right
誰もが正しい
Everyone has an idea, right?
誰もがアイデアを持っていますよね？
what was it like when you were young
若い頃はどうでしたか
The mullet will come
ボラが走ってくる
The mullet will grow soft only in Taiwan
ボラが柔らかくなるのは台湾だけ
That's why there are so many mullet roe in Taiwan
台湾にはカラスミがたくさんあるのはそのためだ
what is this?
これは何ですか？
gift from god
神様からの贈り物
yes
はい
So this is what I'm trying to say
だからこれが私が言いたいことなのです
How did the coming and going of the crowd happen?
群衆の出入りはどのようにして起こったのでしょうか？
In fact, here in Taiwan
実はここ台湾でも
I will also tell you
私もお伝えします
I just returned
たった今帰ってきました
I have no special instructions for you
特別な指示はありません
5000, 4000, 3000, 2000
5000年、4000年、3000年、2000年
These people who live in these Nanke Park in Tainan
台南の南科公園に住んでいる人たち
not the continuation of their lives
彼らの人生の継続ではない
not a continuation of biological life
生物学的生命の継続ではない
Can you understand this sentence
この文を理解できますか
Each varies between 5,000 and 4,000 years
それぞれは5,000年から4,000年の間で変化します
this group of people left
このグループの人々が去った
Like the one we saw 7 meters down
7メートル下で見たのと同じように
it just broke
それはちょうど壊れた
it's gone
なくなってしまった
Another place for another 4,000 years
さらに4000年後も別の場所へ
Its chair is called Youxianfang Chair
その椅子はYouxianfangチェアと呼ばれています
You Xianfang chair we saw
あなたが見たXian Fangチェア
4000 years ago
4000年前
2000 years ago
2000年前
not 3000 years ago
3000年前ではない
what is explained here
ここで説明されていること
Humans choose the one above the living environment
人間は生活環境よりも上のものを選ぶ
Commonality
共通点
Three thousand years ago, it was the one with the highest distribution density in the entire Nanke Park
3000年前、南湖公園全体で最も分布密度が高かった場所
Where did this group of people come from? Actually we are still chasing
このグループはどこから来たのですか? 実は私たちはまだ追いかけています
This is what I have been doing with Mr. Zhang for so many years.
これが私が長年にわたって張氏とやってきたことです。
He let me have a lot of space for these studies
彼は私にこれらの研究のために多くのスペースを与えてくれました
The ecological legacy of our material culture from mischievous, stony assortments
いたずら好きな石の品揃えから得られる私たちの物質文化の生態学的遺産
What we want to chase is no matter where he comes from
私たちが追いたいのは彼がどこから来たとしても
But when he lived in this place
しかし、彼がこの場所に住んでいたとき、
How do they adapt to this environment
彼らはどのようにしてこの環境に適応するのでしょうか
This is what we really want to pursue
これが私たちが本当に追求したいことです
live here live well or not
ここに住んでください、うまく生きるかどうか
i want to tell you
私はあなたに伝えたいです
If what Golanby over there told me was
もしゴランビーがあそこで私に言ったことがそうだとしたら
More than 85% of the time when eating the same type of shellfish
85%以上同じ種類の貝類を食べる
good or bad
良いか悪いか
definitely not good
間違いなく良くない
right
右
This is what I was able to from the archaeological site
これが遺跡から得られたものです
Being able to discover how it behaves on a strategy that keeps them sustainable
持続可能性を維持する戦略に基づいてどのように動作するかを発見できる
Yeah, that's what I've been wanting to share with you all.
そう、それが私が皆さんと共有したいと思っていたことなのです。
We chased from inside the archaeological site to the end guys.
遺跡の中から最後まで追いかけました。
If you just want to chase who it is
誰なのかを追いかけたいだけなら
One day I got a copy, it seems my wife gave it to me
ある日、コピーを手に入れたのですが、妻がそれを私にくれたそうです。
的DNA
のDNA
A test of DNA Now the technology of DNA testing, you can know it by spitting
DNA検査 今ではDNA検査の技術があり、唾を吐けば分かる
how many kinds of people do you have
あなたには何種類の人がいますか
Turns out their first test was
彼らの最初のテストは、
The French must scold the Germans to death, they are so dirty, or something, between each other's workshops, but after a week, they found out that they were still Cutten and the Brothers.
フランス人はドイツ人を死ぬほど叱らなければなりません、彼らはお互いの作業場の間でとても汚いというか何かですが、一週間後に彼らは彼らがまだカッテンと兄弟であることに気づきました。
In my age, Shi Xiaorong, do you know? Shi Xiaorong, when we met on the high-speed rail once, you come to study who I am?
私と同世代の石暁龍さん、知っていますか?石暁龍さん、一度高速鉄道で会ったとき、私が何者なのか勉強しに来ました?
He himself told me that 1/16 of me is Han Chinese, and I am indeed, you can ask him.
彼自身、私の 1/16 はハンだと言いました、そして私は確かにハンです、彼に聞いてみてください。
He said so and so and so and so, how.
彼はああだこうだとこう言った。
So who am I to say that you are? I am patriarchal. Who are the people left in your agreement? It doesn't matter, if you live here, you agree with this place, you agree with this place.
それで、あなたが誰であるかというと、私は何者ですか? 私は家父長制です。あなたの同意書に残っている人は誰ですか? あなたがここに住んでいて、この場所に同意し、この場所に同意しているなら、それは問題ではありません。
Agree with this place, this is the attitude that matters
この場所に同意します、これが重要な態度です
This is what I want to share with you
これが私があなたと共有したいことです
still come, sorry
まだ来ます、ごめんなさい
there are people
人がいます
i want to ask
聞きたいです
Ask Professor Li
李教授に聞く
just inside the archaeological sawdust
考古学的おがくずのすぐ内側
A few of them are thorn slices or peach slices
そのうちのいくつかはトゲのスライスまたは桃のスライスです
That's the blade
それが刃です
what culture is that
それはどんな文化ですか
Niaosong culture
鳥松文化
bird pine iron
鳥松鉄
That's the pavement and that's
あれは舗装、そしてそれは
not tile
タイルではありません
Lay out
レイアウト
Slab
スラブ
tile or
タイルか
Is it paving or
舗装なのか、それとも
Slab
スラブ
I can't see clearly
はっきり見えない
is a tile
タイルです
what does that do
それは何をするのですか
like a floor covering
床材のような
what is it like in culture
文化的にはどうですか
Niaosong culture as we know it now
私たちが今知っているニャオソン文化
I said where did it come from, right?
それがどこから来たのかと言ったよね？
Haruya
哇哉
Ha ha ha ha
ハハハッハッハ
You say that culture is from
文化はから来ているとあなたは言います
that culture
その文化
That culture at that time was the Niaosong culture
その当時の文化がニャオソン文化だった
iron age bird pine
鉄器時代の鳥の松
The second question to ask you
あなたに尋ねる2番目の質問
Dr. Lee, you just said that you are 1/16 Taiwanese
リー博士、あなたは 1/16 台湾人だと言いましたね。
Nah
いや、
Shi Xialong
石暁龍
Teacher, you didn't listen to what you said
先生、言うことを聞いてくれませんでした
Then what is your 15/16?
では、あなたの15/16は何ですか？
I'm not me
私は私じゃない
It's Shixialong
石霞龍です
Shi Xialong
石暁龍
Shi Xialong sings famous songs
石暁龍は有名な歌手です
sing a famous song
有名な歌を歌う
Taiwanese physical education teacher
台湾の体育教師
He is a physical education teacher at the Normal University
彼は師範大学の体育教師です
1 in 16 Taiwanese
台湾人の16人に1人
1 out of 16 Koreans
韓国人の16人に1人
No la
いやラ
he means to say
彼は言い​​たいのです
He's in one of his syndicates
彼は彼のシンジケートの一員です
There are different
違いがある
as if i'm going to tell you guys
まるであなたたちに告げるかのように
I am 2006 07
私は2006 07です
Go to America this year, go to Four Brite in America
今年はアメリカに行って、アメリカのフォーブライトに行きましょう
In our office there is a sister who is tall and burly
私たちのオフィスに背が高くてがっしりしたお姉さんがいる
bright girl
明るい女の子
After I finished speaking, he said I have Shuffle Shape
私が話し終えた後、彼は私がシャッフルシェイプだと言いました。
That is, there is a model behind your front teeth
つまり、切歯の後ろにモデルがあるということです
We call it model incisors
これをモデル切歯と呼びます
What is a model incisor?
モデル切歯とは何ですか?
Model incisors are a feature of Mongolia
模型切歯はモンゴルの特徴
Everyone, you will definitely look in the mirror when you go back.
皆さん、帰ったら必ず鏡を見てください。
There will be model incisors
モデル切歯があります
This Mr. Zhang even wrote the article on the front teeth of the model
この張さんはモデルの前歯についての記事も書いています
good
良い
He is from Central and South America
彼は中南米出身です
He said I have it too
彼は私もそれを持っていると言った
he has too
彼も持っています
Model incisors
モデル切歯
Then I said how could you have
それから私はこう言いました
I go out mother Japanese
日本人のお母さん、出かけます
yes
はい
so this is
それでこれは
We are in every human biological life
私たちはあらゆる人間の生物学的生命の中に存在します
you probably are
あなたはおそらくそうです
Because your genes are likely to be in a certain person
あなたの遺伝子は特定の人のものである可能性が高いため
But how come you don't matter
でもどうしてあなたは関係ないのですか
i still turn around
まだ振り向いてるよ
it doesn't matter what kind of person you are
あなたがどんな人かは関係ありません
When you live in Taiwan and you identify with Taiwan
台湾に住んでいて、台湾に共感するとき
this is important
これは重要
OK
OK
Thanks
ありがとう
Excuse me
すみません
your article first
まずはあなたの記事を
your question first
まずはあなたの質問を
you have a lot of questions
たくさん質問があります
your speech was wonderful
あなたのスピーチは素晴らしかったです
I am a foreigner
私は外国人です
i want to ask a question
私は質問をしたいです
It's because you just broke a bag
それはあなたがバッグを壊したばかりだからです
That is to say, there are many points made of carbon stone mountains
つまり、カーボンストーンの山でできた点がたくさんあるということです。
Is it all your carbon car
それはすべてあなたのカーボンカーですか？
the point of the chair
椅子のポイント
Then do the carbon stone mountain one
それからカーボンストーンマウンテンをやります
A point that is not a chair is a chair
椅子ではない点は椅子です
the back shell of a chair
椅子の背もたれのシェル
the sample taken
採取されたサンプル
the one to do
やるべきこと
Let's talk about the development of the same number
同じ数字の開発について話しましょう
that that
それは
because you said five thousand years
あなたが五千年と言ったから
I think it used to be
前もそうだったと思う
It's like carbon dating
炭素年代測定のようなものだ
I don't know the degree of certainty of your year
あなたの年の確信度がわかりません
Is it possible to use carbon to do it?
カーボンを使用してそれを行うことは可能ですか？
that is to say you
つまりあなたは
yes yes
はいはい
This has
これは持っています
This we send a different lab
これは別のラボに送ります
We send to different labs
さまざまな研究室に派遣しています
with beta
ベータ版あり
also send beta
ベータ版も送信
now present
現在目前
National Taiwan University has a linear accelerator
国立台湾大学には直線加速器がある
before him
彼の前に
We also use the traditional
伝統的なものも使用しています
Liu Songgui's Teacher Liu helped us make it
Liu Songgui の Liu 先生が私たちの制作を手伝ってくれました
So what was done five thousand years ago
では、5000年前に何が行われたのか
is actually more specific
実際にはもっと具体的です
We are now four thousand two to four thousand eight
私たちは現在 4,02 人から 4,088 人です
four thousand two to four thousand eight
4,02 ～ 4,08
we are just
私たちはただです
Humblendon's take it five thousand years
ハンブレンドンは5000年かかる
OK
OK
general anthropology and archeology
一般的な人類学と考古学
They are worried that in this era of colonial
彼らは、この植民地時代において、
used by imperialism
帝国主義によって利用される
That is to say, have you ever considered this problem?
つまり、この問題について考えたことがありますか?
That is to say, will it be possible?
つまり、それは可能でしょうか？
It's just like this, that's colonial
これはまさに植民地時代です
This amperiorism this relationship
この経験主義 この関係
This is the right and wrong place of the position
これはポジションの正しい場所と間違った場所です
i want to tell you
私はあなたに伝えたいです
I used to talk to Xu Zhongwen and Teacher Xu
私は徐仲文と徐先生とよく話しました。
Everyone knows Xu Zhongwen and Mr. Xu
徐仲文と徐氏は誰もが知っています
I had a talk with him
私は彼にあることについて話しました
I said I privately
プライベートで言ってた
Now record it and turn it off
今すぐ録音してオフにしてください
I said
私は言いました
Taiwan is a pirate economy
台湾は海賊経済だ
pirate economy
海賊経済
Surely economists disagree with me
確かに経済学者は私に同意しないでしょう
Pirate economy is
海賊経済は
be more transparent
もっと透明になる
that is
あれは
I'm here, I'll leave after I'm done catching
ここにいるよ、捕まえ終わったら出発するよ
Nobody thinks of this place as the place where I'm going to live here for generations
ここが私が何世代にもわたって住む場所だとは誰も考えていない
I just told him I said
私は彼に言いました、私は言いました
Hey, Nanke has been here for 5,000 years and left, and the one for 4,000 years has come and left
おい、南柯は5000年来て去った、4000年来の南家は来て去った
We all regard this group of people as the first inhabitants of Taiwan
私たちは皆、このグループの人々を台湾の最初の住民だと考えています。
But are these people from the same group?
しかし、これらの人々は同じグループの出身ですか？
i tell you privately
私はあなたに個人的に言います
yes, they are all passers-by
はい、みんな通行人です
Excuse me, if you want the woman of 5,000 years, you will come here after 4,000 years
すみません、5000年の女性が欲しいなら4000年後にここに来てください
Have they tested you for BNO?
BNO の検査を受けましたか?
No
いいえ
I'm sorry, we are now talking about Mr. Zhang
すみません、今は張さんの話です。
we did it but it ain't out yet
やったけどまだ出てない
or we can't do it
あるいはそれはできません
Don't get me wrong, it's not that we can't do it
誤解しないでください、私たちにはそれができないわけではありません
yes we can't do it
はい、それはできません
We have done a lot, just to test
テストのためだけに、私たちはたくさんのことをしてきました
We also sent these specimens to Germany
私たちはこれらの標本をドイツにも送りました
called MACPRAC
MACPRACと呼ばれる
The best organization in the world to make this DNA
このDNAを作る世界最高の組織
We put the mark down, it can't make it
私たちはマークを付けました、それはそれを達成することはできません
Why? Not its experimental parallax
なぜ? 実験的なパララックスではない
because it is a top
トップだから
Because our preservation environment in Taiwan is too poor
台湾での保存環境があまりにも劣悪なため
Because of the DNA that exists in that bone
その骨に存在するDNAのせいで
these things are gone
これらのものはなくなってしまった
So it can't be pulled out, so it can't be made
だから抜かれないから作れない
Then this, if the storage environment is good, there is no problem
これなら保管環境が良ければ問題ない
Like we were recently, our colleagues are on Liang Island in Matsu
最近もそうでしたが、私たちの同僚は馬祖の梁島にいます
Look at him for eight thousand years
八千年も彼を見てください
He also sent the laboratory
彼はまた研究室を送りました
He can do it inside
彼は中でそれができる
Because of the quantity-guided human stock?
量に基づいた人間ストックのせいでしょうか？
It's inside this shell
この殻の中にあります
So shells have a natural
したがって、シェルには自然な性質があります。
can be a function of preservation
保存の役割を果たすことができる
Because it's all that stuffy stuff
それはすべてとても息苦しいものだから
So it can also save
それで節約もできる
its these
それはこれらです
These can be done with DNA
これらはDNAで可能です
these things come out
こういったものが出てくる
But our Nanke stuff
しかし、私たちの南渓のもの
did much
たくさんやった
In Taiwan, we also do Taiwan Majie Hospital
台湾では台湾馬街病院もやってます
Then send it to Bucks Plank in Germany
それからドイツのバックス・プランクに送ります
can't do it
それはできません
now there is a hope
今は希望がある
we send to ireland
私たちはアイルランドに送ります
a lab in ireland
アイルランドの研究室
It is specialized in ear bones
耳の骨に特化しています
the bone inside the ear
耳の中の骨
Then this bone is wrapped in the head
次にこの骨を頭に巻き付けます
maybe it will be better
もしかしたらもっと良くなるかもしれない
and won't
そしてしません
Will not be affected by the outside environment
外部環境の影響を受けません
So now we have a batch of specimens
これで標本のバッチが手に入りました
currently doing
現在実行中
We hope to get a result
結果が出ることを期待しています
maybe there is one
もしかしたら一つあるかもしれない
amazing discovery
驚くべき発見
don't seem to know
知らないようです
the last one
最後のもの
then this one
それからこれ
two more questions
あと2つの質問
please teach me
教えて下さい
Teeth are very important to our life
歯は私たちの命にとってとても大切なものです
If we're missing teeth, find a way to get implants, right?
歯を失ったら、インプラントをする方法を見つけますよね？
Why did Yan Zhiwenming pull out his teeth?
なぜ顔志文明は歯を抜いたのでしょうか？
what do they mean
どういう意味ですか
or why do they think this way
あるいはなぜ彼らはそのように考えるのか
He seems to have pulled out the left and right teeth of the front teeth
前歯の左右を抜いたそうです
Why is there such absorption
なぜそのような吸収が起こるのか
Please advise, thank you
アドバイスしてください、ありがとう
Thank you, this is because I still have two copies, hurry up and get one copy for each person
ありがとうございます。まだ 2 部あるので、急いで 1 人あたり 1 部入手してください
this heavy
この重い
I want to know more about Nanke
南渓についてもっと知りたい
It's okay, you come with me
大丈夫、一緒に来てね
That tooth extraction is, this is what we are talking about
その抜歯は、これが私たちが話していることです
A Cultural Trait of the Someshima Uzu
染島渦の文化的特徴
According to our current understanding
私たちの現在の理解によれば、
it's a symbol of a rite of passage
それは通過儀礼の象徴です
But in our cognition of five thousand years ago
しかし、5000年前の私たちの認識では
Five thousand years ago, both men and women
5000年前、男も女も
But to compare
でも比較すると
Let's say most of this Iron Age happens only to women
この鉄器時代のほとんどが女性だけに起こったとしよう
And women we see now are called mature years
そして今私たちが見ている女性は成熟期と呼ばれています
That is to say, it will be at least 16 years old
つまり、少なくとも16歳以上になります
Occurs after age 16
16歳以降に発症
Let's talk about the size they drew. It is the side door size and the full size.
彼らが描いたサイズについて話しましょう、それはサイドドアのサイズとフルサイズです。
And only pull the top but not the bottom
そして上部だけを引っ張り、下部は引っ張らないでください
This is a cultural characteristic of the Yu people in South Island
これは南島のユ族の文化的特徴です。
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you two teachers for their wonderful speeches
お二人の先生方、素晴らしい講演をありがとうございました
What I want to ask is that there are a lot of naughty people in today's information
聞きたいのは、今日の情報にはエッチな人が多いということです
They do these naughty things to say that everyone can almost do it
彼らは、誰もがそれをほぼ行うことができると言うために、これらのいたずらなことをします
Or is it that they have a dedicated group of people who keep the technique of being naughty?
それとも、エッチなテクニックを維持する熱心な人々がいるということでしょうか？
then maybe better
それならもっと良いかもしれない
Then even do trade or say there is actually no
それから取引をするか、またはないと言うことさえ
Naka didn't mention this
ナカさんはそんなこと言ってなかった
so i'm pretty good
だから私はかなり元気です
Thanks
ありがとう
That's a great question we've also done
これは素晴らしい質問です。私たちもやったことがあります
With Mr. Chen Wenshan, we have worked together from five thousand years, four thousand years, three thousand years
陳文山氏とは、5000年、4000年、3000年にわたって協力してきました。
Different from the analysis of these components above
上記のこれらのコンポーネントの分析とは異なります
We especially do the so-called speech
私たちは特にいわゆるスピーチを行います
It is a component of a stone in a river in your place
それはあなたの場所の川の石の成分です
Let's understand if it's local
地元なら理解しよう
Or from outside
それとも外から
We do see a different phenomenon
確かに別の現象が見られます
For example, 5,000 years ago, 4,000 years ago, and 3,000 years ago
たとえば、5,000 年前、4,000 年前、3,000 年前などです。
There is this difference between the north and the south
北と南ではこんな違いがあるのですね
Even we now think that the place 5,000 years ago belonged to this Penghu
5000年前はこの澎湖のものだったと今の私たちでも思っています。
Or it is likely to be where the ingredient on the other side is located.
あるいは、反対側の材料が配置されている場所である可能性があります。
Because we have seen the so-called
なぜなら、私たちはいわゆるものを見てきたからです。
Not in this place in Tainan
台南にはありません
For example, this burnt black
たとえば、この黒く焼けたもの
Part of the burnt black part belongs to the local
黒く焼けた部分の一部は現地のものです
belonging to the local
地元に所属する
But it has some ingredients that belong to the Zhuoshui River
ただし、卓水川に属する成分がいくつか含まれています
From a face on the other side of Zhuoshui River and Dadu River
卓水河と大渡河の対岸から
So this is not a specialization
だからこれは専門分野ではない
we have now
私たちは今持っています
I'm not doing it later
後はやってないよ
so-called specialization
いわゆる専門性
Or a phenomenon of the so-called logistics
あるいはいわゆる物流現象
Well, we can't see this right now.
まあ、今はこれを見ることはできません。
answer you very specifically
非常に具体的に答えてください
OK
OK
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
Zhang Tianshi in the last two minutes
最後の 2 分間の張天士
there is none left
何も残っていない
no more no more
もうだめ、もうだめ
two minutes
2分
last question
最後一個問題
because you have been there many times
あなたは何度もそこに行ったことがあるから
he has been there many times
彼は何度もそこに行ったことがある
do a lot
たくさんやる
you have been there many times
あなたは何度もそこに行ったことがある
Excuse me, I have doubts because I have been watching that
すみません、それを見ていたので疑問に思ったのですが
Is it because archaeological photos always dig squares?
考古写真はいつも正方形を掘っているからでしょうか？
I know squares are for positioning
正方形は位置を決めるためのものであることは知っています
Then you just dig over there to know where the stuff came from.
それから、そこを掘って、その物がどこから来たのかを知るだけです。
Then I have always had a doubt about the line in the middle of the grid.
それから、私はいつもグリッド中央のラインについて疑問を抱いていました。
That is also a place to walk and a dividing point
そこは歩く場所でもあり、分岐点でもある
if there is
もしあるなら
Will there be any ruins? The relics are buried under that pavilion line.
遺跡はあるのでしょうか? あの東屋のラインの下に遺物が埋まっています。
how to find out
どうやって調べるか
To avoid is to have loaded things being moved
回避するには、荷物を積んで移動することです
Thanks
ありがとう
I'm going to study next semester
私は来学期勉強するつもりです
Ha ha ha ha
ハハハッハッハ
This to Cucumber or to that
これにキュウリ、またはあれに
ok come on good question
わかりました、いい質問をしてください
come to this square
この広場に来てください
If the results of our experiments are theoretically
私たちの実験結果が理論的には
2x2 2 meters by 2 meters
2x2 2メートル×2メートル
This means that the two of you are working inside
つまり、二人は中で働いているということです
3 to 4 is the most cost-effective one
3～4が最も費用対効果が高い
not just positioning
ポジショニングだけではなく
Positioning means that we have this square
位置決めとは、この正方形があることを意味します
Everything comes out of this
すべてはここから生まれる
We put it away layer by layer
一層ずつ片づけていきます
is to tell us the up and down of these things
これらの物事の上下を伝えることです
The positions of these relationships in space cannot be mixed up
空間におけるこれらの関係の位置を混同することはできません
But there is a line
でも線はあるよ
you see the line
線が見えます
That is what we call borrowing strength
それが「力を借りる」ということです
A method of excavating an early tradition
初期の伝統を発掘する方法
at the end you have something inside
最後には中に何かが入っています
It's like a person's upper body is in
人の上半身が入っているような感じです
The lower body in the carbon pit is in the middle of the divider
カーボンピット内の下半身はディバイダーの真ん中にあります
then i will cut it off
それから私はそれを切ります
grab it
それをつかむ
kill
殺す
spank all the way to that
そこまで叩きます
is not possible
不可能である
But now there are so-called
しかし今では、いわゆる
One of our excavations in Nanke
南柯での発掘調査のひとつ
the whole compartment
コンパートメント全体
no middle no bit
真ん中じゃない、ちょっと
But we jumped and dug. If there is a phenomenon in the middle, we have to dig a hole.
しかし、飛び降りて掘ったので、途中で現象があれば穴を掘らなければなりません。
In the end, there will be a flat phenomenon
最終的にはフラット現象が起こるだろう
different from mainland China
中国本土とは違う
When we talk to them in mainland China
中国本土で彼らと話をすると、
He said your kind of digging children
彼はあなたが子供たちを掘っていると言いました
When we dig 10 meters, we call it 10 meters
10メートル掘ると10メートルと言います。
They are called Dafang Carbon Fang
彼らはDafang Carbon Fangと呼ばれています
yes
はい
Then this is a different way of excavation
それから、これは別の発掘方法です
it's different in america
アメリカでは違うよ
What we do in the United States is not changed at all
アメリカでやっていることは全く変わっていない
You just take one of your phenomena
自分の現象の 1 つを取り上げるだけです
But between layers
でも層の間では
between this direction
この方向の間
this is still important
これはまだ重要です
That means all of our unearthed stuff
それは私たちが発掘したすべてのものを意味します
They all have their ID cards
彼らは全員IDカードを持っています
Otherwise, you can talk nonsense when the time comes
そうしないと、いざという時にくだらない話をしてもいいのです
Mix up the top with the bottom
上と下を混ぜ合わせます
natural mix
ナチュラルミックス
That is the one that got mixed up in the first place. If you mess with this side, then this is the most irrelevant thing. I can’t say that again.
そもそもそっちがごちゃ混ぜだったんだ、こっちをいじるならこっちが一番関係ないんだよ、もうそんなことは言えないよ。
I suggest that you have the opportunity to host one and ask him for advice in private, because at 9:00
9時に開催されるので、プライベートでアドバイスを求める機会を持つことをお勧めします。
The main team went to visit, you see his 5,000-year-old man is sleeping next to 200-year-old
主要チームが訪問しました。5,000歳の男性が200歳の男性の隣で眠っているのがわかります。
I feel that there is a lot of time. In Nanke and Tainan Science Park, there is no
時間はたくさんあると感じますが、南科と台南サイエンスパークには時間がありません。
Not yet, thank you two for their wonderful speeches, thank you for participating
まだです、お二人の素晴らしいスピーチに感謝します、ご参加いただきありがとうございます